<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Items</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://thedeckofmany.com/">Deck of Many</author>
		<update version="0.0.3">
			<file name="Magic-item.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/th3R3df0xx/Dnd/master/Humblewood/Magic-item.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
    <element name="Blade of the Wood" type="Magic Item" source="Humblewood" id="ID_DOM_H_MAGIC_ITEM_BLADE_OF_THE_WOOD">		
		<description>
			<p>A finely crafted sword with delicate etchings, it resonates
                with a faint hum of life.
                You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with
                this magic weapon.
                The sword has 2 charges. You can expend a charge and
                speak the command word to cast spike growth (save DC
                16) centered on yourself. You can pass through this terrain
                unaffected.
                The sword regains one charge each day at dawn.</p>
				</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Gulthias Staff" type="Magic Item" source="Curse of Strahd" id="ID_WOTC_COS_MAGIC_ITEM_GULTHIAS_STAFF">		
		<description>
			<p>THE BOREALUS
                Staff, artifact (requires attunement)
                This legendary artifact was created by a powerful wizard,
                crafted from the finger of a towering, ancient elemental aspect
                of frost. It is so cold to the touch that it numbs any skin it
                comes into contact with, although an attuned character is
                immune to this effect.
               <b> Gifts of the Rime.</b> As long as you are attuned to the Borealus,
                you gain the following benefits:
                * You are resistant to fire damage
                * You are immune to cold damage
                * You learn the ray of frost cantrip
               <b>Breath of Winter.</b>  While holding the staff you can use your
                action to unleash an icy-cold blizzard from your open mouth.
                A 100-foot-cone of hoarfrost blasts forth in a direction of your
                choice, dealing 9d8 cold damage to all creatures within the
                cone if they fail a DC 18 Constitution saving throw, or half as
                much on a success. You can’t use this property again until the
                next dawn.
                <b>Glacial Prison.</b> By using your action to touch the staff to
                a surface, you can cause a barrier of ice to spring into existence
                from a point you can see along this surface within 200 feet
                of you. This effect is otherwise identical to a wall of ice spell
                cast at 6th level, with a DC 18 for all saving throws related
                to the effect. You can’t use this property again until 3 days
                have passed.
               <b> Cruel Winds.</b> Wherever the staff goes, a bitterly cold
                boreal wind accompanies it. The wind gusts intermittently
                within 30 feet of the attuned character and extinguishes all
                non-magical flames it comes into contact with.
                Destroying the Staff. The staff can be destroyed through
                exposure to flames from a fire elemental of equal power to the
                being it was crafted from. After centuries of exposure, it will
                melt away into nothing.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<rules>
                
            </rules>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Holy Symbol of Ravenkind" type="Magic Item" source="Curse of Strahd" id="ID_WOTC_COS_MAGIC_ITEM_HOLY_SYMBOL_OF_RAVENKIND">		
		<description>
			<p>The Holy Symbol of Raven kind is a unique holy symbol sacred to the good-hearted faithful of Barovia. It predates the establishment of any church in Barovia. According to legend, it was delivered to a paladin named Lugdana by a giant raven-or an angel in the form of a giant raven. Lugdana used the holy symbol to root out and destroy nests of vampires until her death. The high priests of Ravenloft kept and wore the holy symbol after Lugdana's passing.</p>
			<p class="indent">The holy symbol is a platinum amulet shaped like the sun, with a large crystal embedded in its center.</p>
			<p class="indent">The holy symbol has 10 charges for the following properties. It regains 1d6 + 4 charges daily at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Hold Vampires.</em></strong> As an action, you can expend 1 charge and present the holy symbol to make it flare with holy power. Vampires and vampire spawn within 30 feet of the holy symbol when it flares must make a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, a target is paralyzed for 1 minute. It can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns to end the effect on itself.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Turn Undead.</em></strong> If you have the-Turn Undead or the Turn the Unholy feature, you can expend 3 charges when you present the holy symbol while using that feature. When you do so, undead have disadvantage on their saving throws against the effect.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sunlight.</em></strong> As an action, you can expend 5 charges while presenting the holy symbol to make it shed bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. The light is sunlight and lasts for 10 minutes or until you end the effect (no action required).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a cleric or paladin of good alignment">true</set>
			<set name="charges">10</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Icon of Ravenloft" type="Magic Item" source="Curse of Strahd" id="ID_WOTC_COS_MAGIC_ITEM_ICON_OF_RAVENLOFT">		
		<description>
			<p>The Icon of Raven loft is a 12-inch-tall statuette made of the purest silver, weighing 10 pounds. It depicts a cleric kneeling in supplication.</p>
			<p class="indent">The icon was given to Strahd by the archpriest Ciril Romulich, an old family friend, to consecrate the castle and its chapel.</p>
			<p class="indent">While within 30 feet of the icon, a creature is under the effect of a protection from evil and good spell against fiends and undead. Only a creature attuned to the icon can use its other properties.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Augury.</em></strong> You can use an action to cast an <em>augury</em> spell from the icon, with no material components required. Once used, this property can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Bane of the Undead.</em></strong> You can use the icon as a holy symbol while using the Turn Undead or Turn the Unholy feature. If you do so, increase the save DC by 2.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Cure Wounds.</em></strong> While holding the icon, you can take an action to heal one creature that you can see within 30 feet of you. The target regains 3d8 + 3 hit points, unless it is an undead, a construct, or a fiend. Once used, this property can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a creature of good alignment">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Saint Markovia’s Thighbone" type="Magic Item" source="Curse of Strahd" id="ID_WOTC_COS_MAGIC_ITEM_SAINT_MARKOVIAS_THIGHBONE">		
		<description>
			<p>Saint Markovia's thighbone has the properties of a mace of disruption. If it scores one or more hits against a vampire or a vampire spawn in the course of a single battle, the thighbone crumbles into dust once the battle concludes.</p>
			<p class="indent">As a youth, Markovia followed her heart and became a priest of the Morninglord soon after her eighteenth birthday. She proved to be a charismatic proselytizer and, before the age of thirty, had gained a reputation for allowing no evil to stand before her.</p>
			<p class="indent">Markovia had long considered Strahd a mad tyrant, but only after his transformation into a vampire did she dare to challenge him. As she rallied her followers and prepared to march on Castle Ravenloft, Strahd sent a group of vampire spawn to her abbey. They confronted Markovia and were destroyed to a one.</p>
			<p class="indent">Suffused with confidence born of righteous victory, Markovia advanced on Castle Ravenloft. A great battle raged from the catacombs to the parapets. In the end, Markovia never returned to Barovia, and Strahd long afterward walked with a limp and a grimace of pain. It is said that he trapped Markovia in a crypt beneath his castle, and her remains linger there yet.</p>
			<p class="indent">The essence of Markovia's saintliness passed partly into her bones as the rest of her body decomposed. Her remaining thighbone is imbued with power that inflicts grievous injury on the undead.</p>
			<!-- mace, mace of disruption, this -->
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_MACE_OF_DISRUPTION" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="mace">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Mace</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sunsword" type="Magic Item" source="Curse of Strahd" id="ID_WOTC_COS_MAGIC_ITEM_SUNSWORD">		
		<description>
			<p>The <em>Sunsword</em> is a unique blade once possessed by Strahd's brother, Sergei von Zarovich. In its original form, it had a platinum hilt and guard, and a thin crystal blade as strong as steel.</p>
			<p class="indent">Strahd employed a powerful wizard named Khazan to destroy the weapon after Sergei's death. The first part of the process required the hilt and the blade to be separated, which Khazan accomplished. While Khazan was busying himself destroying the blade, his apprentice stole the hilt and fled. Khazan later located his apprentice's mutilated corpse in the Svalich Woods, but the hilt was nowhere to be found. To avoid the vampire's wrath, Khazan told Strahd that the entire weapon had been destroyed.</p>
			<p class="indent">The hilt, which is sentient, knows that it can never be reunited with its original crystal blade. It has, however, gained the properties of a <em>sun blade</em>.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sentience.</em></strong> The <em>Sunsword</em> is a sentient chaotic good weapon with an Intelligence of 11, a Wisdom of 17, and a Charisma of 16. It has hearing and normal vision out to a range of 60 feet. The weapon communicates by transmitting emotions to the creature carrying or wielding it.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Personality.</em></strong> The <em>Sunsword</em>'s special purpose is to destroy Strahd, not so much because it wants to free the land of Barovia from evil but because it wants revenge for the loss of its crystal blade. The weapon secretly fears its own destruction.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Lost Sword" type="Magic Item" source="Curse of Strahd" id="ID_WOTC_COS_MAGIC_ITEM_LOST_SWORD">		
		<description>
			<p>An unnamed sentient shortsword.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">The sword continually sheds bright light in a 15-foot radius and dim light for an additional 15 feet. Only by destroying the sword can this light be extinguished.</p>
			<p class="indent">A lawful good creature can attune itself to the sword in 1 minute.</p>
			<p class="indent">While attuned to the weapon, the sword’s wielder can use the sword to cast the <em>crusader’s mantle</em> spell. Once used, this property of the sword can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sentience.</em></strong> The sword is a lawful good weapon with an Intelligence of 11, a Wisdom of 13, and a Charisma of 13. It has hearing and normal vision out to a range of 120 feet. The weapon communicates by transmitting emotion to the creature carrying or wielding it.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Personality.</em></strong> The sword’s purpose is to fight evil.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shortsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Shortsword</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a lawful good creature">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CRUSADERS_MANTLE" requirements="ID_ALIGNMENT_LAWFUL_GOOD" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
