<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
<info>
		<name>Humblewood spells</name>
		
		<author url="https://thedeckofmany.com/">Deck of Many</author>
		<update version="0.0.4">
			<file name="Spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/th3R3df0xx/Dnd/master/Humblewood/Spells.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Ambush Prey" type="Spell" source="Humblewood" id="ID_H_SPELL_AMBUSH_PREY">
		<supports>Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="indent">
			You channel primal predatory energies to perfectly conceal
your presence in order to surprise your target. You become
invisible for the spell’s duration, granting advantage on all
Dexterity (Stealth) checks to remain hidden. The invisibility
will last for the duration of the spell, however, moving 5 feet
or more from your position when you cast the spell will end
the effect.
As long as you remain invisible, the first attack you make
against any target who is unaware of your presence deals an
additional 1d6 points of damage. This attack ends the spell.
<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b>
				 When you cast this spell using a spell
slot above 2nd level, the damage of your first attack increases
by 1d6 for every slot level above 2nd.		
			</p>
			

		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">illusion</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 Hour</set>
			<set name="range">self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a broken twig</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Elevated Sight" type="Spell" source="Humblewood" id="ID_H_SPELL_ELEVATED_SIGHT">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Ranger, Cleric, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="indent">
			

You cast your eyes skyward, granting you sight from a
higher vantage point. You project your vision to see through an
invisible sensor which appears in a spot up to 120 feet above
you. You can see through the sensor as if you were flying,
granting a full 360 degree view from its location.
The sensor moves with you, retaining its height in relation
to you. You can use a bonus action to adjust the sensor’s
height, but only to a maximum of 120 feet above you.
While looking through this sensor you are blind, though
you can switch between seeing through the sensor or through
your own eyes at any time during your turn.

		</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters></element>
    	<element name="Feathered Reach" type="Spell" source="Humblewood" id="ID_H_SPELL_FEATHERED_REACH">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="indent">
You transform your arms into powerful wings, and your
fingers into long, graceful feathers. The effects of this spell
last 1 minute, at which point the feathers gradually fall out,
causing you to float gently to the ground as your arms return
to their original form. This spell confers a number of benefits
upon the caster:</p>
			<p class="indent">*As a bonus action, you can fly up to double your movement
speed. You must land once you finish your movement,
although you do not take fall damage while this
spell is active, as your feathered arms bear you gently to
the ground</p>
			<p class="indent">*You can use your powerful feathered arms to propel yourself
upward a distance equal to half your movement speed.
You can do this once during your turn and may use it in
conjunction with a regular jump.</p>
			<p class="indent">*When falling, you can use your reaction to stiffen your
arms, and glide on the wind. You may fly up to your movement
speed, in any direction, choosing where you land.</p>
						<p class="indent">*You gain advantage on all athletics checks used to make a
long or high jump. You do not need to move 10 feet before
you jump to gain distance, and you triple the distance you
would jump normally.</p>
			<p class="indent">In order to benefit from this spell your hands must
be free of shields and heavy weapons, and you cannot
be encumbered</p>
			

		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a small feather</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Globe of Twilight" type="Spell" source="Humblewood" id="ID_H_SPELL_GLOBE_OF_TWILIGHT">
		<supports>Druid, Warlock, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="indent"> You shroud the area surrounding you in a sphere
of night sky, dotted with miniature stars. The twilight
conceals your allies, but clearly illuminates your enemies.
The area affected by this spell is lightly obscured by
magical shadow, within which small constellations softly
twinkle. Aside from these stars, only light produced by
a spell of 3rd level or higher can properly illuminate any
area inside the sphere. Nonmagical light does not function
inside the sphere, and all other forms of magical
radiance can only produce dim light in a 5-foot space.
When you cast this spell you may designate any number
of creatures you can see to be concealed by the supernatural
shadows while in the sphere. A concealed creature has advantage
on Dexterity (Stealth) checks when inside the sphere and
may attempt to hide at any time. Because the area of the spell
is lightly obscured, creatures within the spell’s area have disadvantage
on Wisdom (Perception) checks made to see those
outside of it.

		</p>
		<p class="indent">All other creatures in the area are dazzled by the light of
the miniature stars, causing them to have disadvantage on all
perception checks inside the sphere. When such a creature
enters the spell’s area for the first time, or starts its turn there,
it must make a Wisdom saving throw or be blinded until the
end of its turn.
</p>
		
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">10 minute</set>
			<set name="range">self (15-foot radius, 15 feet high)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a dab of pitch and a bag of glittering sand</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>

</element>
	<element name="Gust Barrier" type="Spell" source="Humblewood" id="ID_H_SPELL_GUST_BARRIER">
		<supports>Wizard, Druid, Bard, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="indent">
			
You spread your arms wide, allowing yourself to become
enveloped by the air around you. Until the end of your next
turn, any ranged attack made against you is done
with disadvantage.
Melee attackers who successfully hit you must make a
Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. On a
failure, the attacker is flung away from you up to 10 feet and is
knocked prone.

		</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="range">self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
</element>
	<element name="Invoke the Amaranthine" type="Spell" source="Humblewood" id="ID_H_SPELL_INVOKE_THE_AMARANTHINE">
		<supports> Cleric, Paladin</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="indent">
			





You call upon the power of an Amaranthine to grant
yourself insight into the Great Rhythm that moves all
things. When you cast this spell, roll two d20s, and record
what you rolled. For each die, choose either attack roll,
skill check, or saving throw. You can choose each option
multiple times. For the next 24 hours, you may substitute
any roll of an ally or enemy you can see within 60 feet
with one of the recorded numbers that matches the type of
roll you wish to replace (attack roll, skill check, or saving
throw). The target still adds any relevant modifiers to this
number, but otherwise treat the substituted number as the
number they rolled.
To do this, you must spend a reaction to present your
holy symbol and invoke the name of the Amaranthine
whose energies you called upon. You can do this anytime
after the skill check, saving throw or attack has been rolled,
but before the outcome of the event has been determined.
The spell ends after 24 hours have passed, or when both
dice have been expended.
		</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">24 hour</set>
			<set name="range">self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">  (a holy symbol of the Amaranthine)</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
</element>
	<element name="Shape Plants" type="Spell" source="Humblewood" id="ID_H_SPELL_SHAPE_PLANTS">
		<supports>Bard, Cleric, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="indent">
			


You call upon gentle natural magics to alter the growth
of plants. Any plant life you can see within range that fits
within a 5-foot cube can take on whatever shape you desire.
Additionally, if the plant is a bramble, or capable of growing
thorns, you turn the affected area into difficult terrain, causing
2d4 points of piercing damage for every 5 feet moved through
the area you shaped. You may also increase or decrease the
number of flowers, vines, leaves, thorns, branches, or fruits
produced by any plant you shape.
After one hour, the magic of your spell fades, and the plant
resumes its normal shape. If you can use speak with plants
(or a similar ability) to communicate with the plant, you may
persuade it to retain its new form. Different plants have different
feelings and attitudes, and if the form is too different from
its natural shape it is likely to decline. If the plant accepts, at
the GM’s discretion, it will retain the
form you have sculpted it into, in which case the effect
becomes permanent.
<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b>
				 When you cast this spell using a spell
slot above 4th level, the size of the cube of plant life you can
affect with the spell increases by an additional 5 feet for every
slot level above 4th.

		</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration"> Instantaneous; Special, see text</set>
			<set name="range">touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
</element>
	<element name=" Spiny Shield" type="Spell" source="Humblewood" id="ID_H_SPELL_SPINY_SHIELD">
		<supports>Wizard,  Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="indent">
			



An ethereal barrier of spikes, made of magical force,
interposes itself between you and an attacker. Until your next
turn, when you are hit by a melee attack, the barrier reduces
the damage your are dealt by 2d4, and deals the same amount
of piercing damage to the attacker. The shield is ineffective
against ranged attackers, but still provides a +2 bonus to AC
(treat as half cover) against them for the duration.
At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell
slot above 1st level, increase the spell’s effect by an additional
1d4 for every slot level above 1st.
		</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 Round</set>
			<set name="range">self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">(a small quill)</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
</element>
	<element name=" Stellar Bodies" type="Spell" source="Humblewood" id="ID_H_SPELL_STELLAR_BODIES">
		<supports>Wizard, Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="indent">
			




You create two small stars that orbit you. They twinkle
pleasantly, shedding dim light in a 10-foot radius centered
on you. The stars protect you. If a creature within 5 feet of
you hits you with a melee attack they must make a Wisdom
saving throw or take 1d8 points of radiant damage for each star
orbiting you.
Once per round, on your turn, you may use your action
to cause a star to streak towards an enemy, expending it as it
explodes in a blinding flash. Make a ranged spell attack against
an enemy within 120 feet, dealing 4d8 points of radiant
damage on a hit. The target must then make a Constitution
saving throw or be blinded until the start of your next turn.
The spell ends when either its duration expires, you fall
unconscious, or you have expended all of your stars.
At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell
slot above 4th level, you may create one additional star for
every two slot levels above 4th. For each additional star
orbiting you, the radius of dim light centered on you increases
by 5 feet.
		</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range"> Special, see text</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
</element>
	<element name="Veil of Dusk" type="Spell" source="Humblewood" id="ID_H_SPELL_VEIL_OF_DUSK">
		<supports> Warlock, Druid </supports>
		<description>
			<p class="indent">

You incant towards a creature, cloaking them in a shadowy
veil of darkness and silence. The target gains a +1 bonus to
their armor class and rolls stealth checks with advantage for the
duration of the spell.
		</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">(a pinch of soot)</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
</element>
	</elements>



