<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <update version="0.0.6">
            <file name="Source.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/th3R3df0xx/Dnd/master/Purple-Aether-Games/Source.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="The Elemental Spellbook" type="Source" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_JACOB_THE_ELEMENTAL_SPELLBOOK">
        <description>
            <p>There just aren’t enough elemental spells in the Player’s Handbook. Players who want their sorcerer to stick to a tight theme are instead forced to learn off-theme spells, even after palette-swapping large numbers of damage spells. Dungeon Masters looking to populate a fire cult or other themed content face a similar obstacle. Well, worry no more. With nothing but this compendium and the Player’s Handbook, you can take your favorite elemental mage all the way from 1st to 20th level while remaining devoted to your concept, even if you’re dedicated to a single element. In this document, you’ll find 80 new spells, spread across fire, ice, and lightning themes and covering every spell level—even new cantrips. Below is a list of every spell, sorted by spell level. After that, the spell descriptions are sorted by type (cold, fire, then lightning) and presented alphabetically. Of course, these spells aren’t exclusive to tightlythemed elemental mages! Work with your DM to determine which spells might be most appropriate for your character.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">ES</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.dmsguild.com/product/290379/The-Elemental-Spellbook-80-Spells-of-Ice-Fire-and-Lightning</set>
            <set name="image">https://www.dmsguild.com/images/8957/290379.png</set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="Jacob" url="https://www.dmsguild.com/product/290379/The-Elemental-Spellbook-80-Spells-of-Ice-Fire-and-Lightning">Jacob S Kellogg</set>
            <set name="third-party">true</set>   
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>
