<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>

 <info>
    <name>Spells</name>
    <description>Spells from the Elmental spellbook.</description>
    <author url="https://www.dmsguild.com/product/290379/The-Elemental-Spellbook-80-Spells-of-Ice-Fire-and-Lightning">Purple Aether Games</author>
		<update version="0.1.3">
			<file name="Spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/th3R3df0xx/Dnd/master/Purple-Aether-Games/The-Elemental-Spellbook/Spells.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Agonizing Chill" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_AGONIZING_CHILL">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You afflict a creature you can see within range with a crippling cold that fills its entire body. 
				The creature immediately takes 3d10 cold damage, then must make a Constitution saving throw or be affected by the spell for the duration. 
				A creature that is immune to cold damage is unaffected by this spell. An affected creature's movements are slowed by the oppressive cold filling its body.
				Its speed is halved; it suffers a –2 penalty to its AC; it has disadvantage on attack rolls, Dexterity checks, and Dexterity saving throws; 
				it has disadvantage on Constitution saving throws to maintain concentration on spells; 
				it can take either an action or a bonus action on its turn, but not both; and it can't take reactions.
				At the end of each of the affected creature's turns, it can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect onitself on a success. 
				On a failed save, the creature takes an additional 3d10 cold damage. 
				At Higher Levels. 
				When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, 
				you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 5th.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 Minute</set>
			<set name="range">90 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Arctic Wind" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ARCIC_WIND">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="indent">A line of frigid wind 120 feet long and 15 feet wide blasts from you in a direction you choose for the spell's duration. Whenever a creature starts its turn in the line, that creature takes 5d8 cold damage and must make a Strength saving throw or be pushed 30 feet away from you in a direction following the line.</p>
			<p class="indent">Any creature in the line must spend 2 feet of movement for every 1 foot it moves when moving closer to you.</p>
			<p class="indent">The wind disperses gas or vapor, and it extinguishes all nonmagical flames in the area, even protected flames such as those of lanterns. Magical flames in the area are immediately dispelled.</p>
			<p class="indent">As a bonus action on each of your turns before the spell ends, you can change the direction in which the line blasts from you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school">evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">self(120-foot line)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Aurora Blast" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_AURORA_BLAST">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You call upon the frigid power of arctic nights, summoning multicolored beams of light to strike your foes with supernatural cold.</p>
			<p class="indent">Eight beams of vivid light streak down from the sky at points you choose within range. Each beam is 10 feet wide, and each must strike a different point, although a big enough creature may be struck by multiple beams.</p>
			<p class="indent">A creature struck by one or more beams must make a Constitution saving throw, taking 20d6 colddamage per beam on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school">evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">500 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">False</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Blizzard" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_BLIZZARD">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Until the spell ends, heavy snow swirls through the air throughout a 50-foot-tall cylinder with a 100-foot radius centered on a point you choose within range. The area is lightly obscured, exposed flames in the area are doused, and ranged attack rolls in the area have disadvantage. Thick snow coats the ground in the area, making it difficult terrain.</p>
			<p class="indent">When the blizzard appears, each creature in the area must make a Constitution saving throw, taking 4d10 cold damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one. A creature must also make this saving throw when it enters the spell's area for the first time on a turn or ends its turn there. If a creature is flying when it fails this saving throw, the creature falls to the ground.</p>
			<p class="indent">You are unaffected by this spell. Additionally, you may designate a number of other creatures up to your spellcasting ability modifier to also be unaffected by this spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 Minute</set>
			<set name="range">150 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Coldsnap" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_COLDSNAP">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>An aura of cold air and a pale blue light radiates out from you to a distance of 30 feet. This area moves with you and stays centered on you. Whenever a creature within this spell's area takes cold damage from a spell you cast, increase that damage by 2d6.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 Minute</set>
			<set name="range">self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Comet Strike" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_COMET_STRIKE">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A 20-foot radius sphere of dirty ice plummets to the ground on a point you can see within range. Each creature in the area of impact must make a Strength saving throw. A creature which fails its save takes 4d8 bludgeoning damage and 4d6 cold damage and is knocked prone. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and does not fall prone. Objects in the area are also damaged. The comet dissolves immediately after impact.
			
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b>
				When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the bludgeoning damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 5th.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">400 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a tiny pebble</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Cryostasis" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_CRYOSTASIS">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You encase a willing creature in a cocoon of ice, putting it in a state of suspended animation until the spell ends. The creature is unconscious until the spell ends. Time does not pass for the creature while the spell is active.</p>
			<p class="indent">The icy casing is immune to all damage. The spell ends if the ice is affected by a disintegrate spell. Ability checks made to dispel this spell via dispel magic are made with disadvantage. Spells and other effects are unable to pass through the ice to affect the creature inside.</p>
			<p class="indent">Upon casting this spell, you can designate an amount of time after which the spell will end on its own, safely releasing the encased creature.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school">abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 hour</set>
			<set name="duration">Until dispelled</set>
			<set name="range">touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a diamond worth 1,000 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Deep Freeze" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_DEEP_FREEZE">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				You attempt to turn one creature that you can see
				within range into solid ice. The creature must make
				a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it is
				restrained as its body begins to harden, and it gains
				vulnerability to fire damage. On a successful save,
				the creature isn’t affected. A creature that is immune
				to cold damage is unaffected by this spell.
				A creature restrained by this spell must make
				another Constitution saving throw at the end of
				each of its turns. If it successfully saves against this
				spell three times, the spell ends. If it fails its saves
				three times, it is turned to ice and subjected to the
				petrified condition (except for its continued
				vulnerability to fire damage) for the duration. The
				successes and failures don’t need to be consecutive;
				keep track of both until the target collects three of a
				kind. If the affected creature takes fire damage, it
				has advantage on its next saving throw.
				If the creature is physically broken while frozen, it
				suffers from similar deformities if it reverts to its
				original state.
				If you maintain your concentration on this spell
				for the entire possible duration, the creature is
				turned to ice until the effect is removed.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 Action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Flashfreeze" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_FLASHFREEZE">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>

			<p>
				You attempt to instantly freeze a target solid.
				Choose one Medium or smaller creature you can see
				within range. If that creature fails a Constitution
				saving throw, it freezes in place and is paralyzed for
				the duration.
				A creature that is immune to cold damage is
				unaffected by this spell and a creature that is
				resistant to cold damage has advantage on the
				saving throw.
				As long as a creature is paralyzed by this spell, it
				has vulnerability to fire damage. However, if the
				creature takes at least 10 points of fire damage at
				once, that creature is no longer affected by this spell.
				An affected creature can repeat the saving throw
				at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on
				itself on a success.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b>
				When you cast this spell using a
				spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can target one
				additional creature for each slot level above 3rd. For
				every two creatures you could target, you can
				instead choose to target a single Large creature.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 Action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Foot Freeze" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_FOOT_FREEZE">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				You cause thick frost to form around a creature's
				feet to immobilize it. Choose a creature you can see
				within range that is touching a floor or other
				surface. The creature must succeed on a Dexterity
				saving throw or be frozen to the surface. If the
				surface is immobile, the creature's speed is reduced
				to 0.
				The frost dissolves at the end of the affected
				creature's turn. An affected creature can break free
				early by spending an action.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 Action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Frigid Barrier" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_FRIGID_BARRIER">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				You create sheets of ice on one or more solid
				surfaces within range. Each sheet is a 5-foot-square
				panel that's 1 foot thick, and you can create a
				number of sheets up to your spellcasting ability
				modifier. The panels can be in any orientation as
				long as at least one edge of each panel is anchored
				to a solid surface or another panel, although a
				particularly lopsided structure may collapse.
				If a panel cuts through a creature's space when it
				appears, that creature is pushed to the nearest
				unoccupied space and must make a Dexterity saving
				throw, taking 2d8 cold damage on a failed save or
				half as much damage on a successful one.
				As a bonus action on each of your turns for the
				duration, you can create or dissolve any number of
				panels, as long as there are never more panels in
				place at one time than your spellcasting ability
				modifier.
				These sheets of ice are objects that can be
				damaged and therefore breached. Each panel has AC
				10 and 20 hit points, and is vulnerable to fire
				damage.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 Action</set>
			<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a tiny sheet of glass</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Frigid Grasp" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_FRIGID_GASP">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				You reach out and touch a creature, shocking its
				system with sudden cold. Make a melee spell attack.
				On a hit, the target takes 1d12 cold damage.
				This spell's damage increases by 1d12 when you
				reach 5th level (2d12), 11th level (3d12), and 17th level
				(4d12).
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 Action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Frost Trap" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_FROST_TRAP">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				A weapon, claw, fist, or other physical attack is
				abruptly chilled upon contact with you. The
				attacking creature must make a Dexterity saving
				throw. If the creature fails, then the weapon (or
				body part, in the case of unarmed or natural attacks)
				is frozen to your body and cannot be used until
				freed.
				The frost dissolves at the beginning of the affected
				creature's next turn. The spell can be ended early if a
				creature within reach uses an action to pull the
				weapon free of the frost.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you are hit by a weapon attack</set>
			<set name="duration">1 Round</set>
			<set name="range">self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ice Beam" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ICE_BEAM">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				A beam of pale blue light forming a line 30 feet
				long and 5 feet wide flashes out from your
				outstretched hand in a direction you choose. Each
				creature in the line must make a Dexterity saving
				throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d8 cold
				damage, and until the beginning of your next turn
				its speed is halved and it can't take reactions. On a
				successful save, a creature takes half as much
				damage and does not suffer the other effects.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b>
				When you cast this spell using a
				spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage
				increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 Action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Self (30-foot line)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an oblong bead of blue glass</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ice Blade" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ICE_BLADE">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				You conjure three snowflakes the size of saw
				blades in your space. The blades spin in the air and
				orbit around you for the duration.
				When you cast this spell and as a bonus action on
				each of your turns thereafter, you can launch any
				number of the blades toward one or more targets
				within 120 feet of you. Make a ranged spell attack for
				each blade. On a hit, a blade deals 1d8 slashing
				damage and 2d4 cold damage. Regardless of whether
				an attack hits or misses, all blades return to your
				space immediately after the attack.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b>
				When you cast this spell using a
				spell slot of 5th level or higher, you create one
				additional blade for each slot level above 4th.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 Action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ice Body" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ICE_BODY">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>

				You change yourself into a being of magical ice.
				You keep your general size and shape and retain all
				your abilities, but equipment that you are wearing
				melds into your body and ceases to function for the
				duration.
				While under the effects of this spell, you have
				vulnerability to fire damage; immunity to cold and
				poison damage; and resistance to bludgeoning,
				piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical
				weapons. Additionally, whenever a creature hits you
				with a melee attack or ends its turn in direct
				contact with you (such as through a grapple), that
				creature takes 1d6 cold damage.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b>
				When you cast this spell using a
				spell slot of 6th or 7th level, the duration increases
				to 8 hours. When you cast this spell using a spell slot
				of 8th or 9th level, the duration increases to 24
				hours.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 Action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ice Cave" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ICE_CAVE">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				Ice Cave
				7th-level conjuration
				Casting Time: 1 action
				Range: Self
				Components: V, S, M (a hollow glass orb)
				Duration: Concentration, up to 10 minutes
				You encase your surroundings with ice, locking
				yourself and nearby creatures in a cave-like prison of
				ice. The maximum size of the enclosure is a 60-footradius
				sphere centered on you, but sturdy surfaces
				will be lined with ice to form the interior contours
				of the area. The ice is 6 inches thick where layered
				onto existing surfaces, and 3 feet thick where freestanding.
				If the ice cuts through a creature's space, the
				creature is pushed either inside or outside the
				enclosure (your choice). When the ice appears, you
				can cause up to 10 icy stalactites or stalagmites to
				form, jabbing abruptly inward from the walls, floor,
				or ceiling of the ice cave. Each spike is 5 feet long
				and 3 feet wide at the base. A creature whose space
				gets spiked must make a Dexterity saving throw,
				taking 2d8 piercing damage and 3d6 cold damage per
				spike on a failed save, or half as much damage on a
				successful one.
				As a bonus action on each of your turns, you can
				cause up to 5 spikes to erupt or dissolve (or a mix of
				both).
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school">conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 Action</set>
			<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">Hallow glass Orb</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ice Mountain" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ICE_MOUNTAIN">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				With a gesture, you cause a glacial mountain of ice
				to erupt from the ground at a point you choose
				within range. The mountain is 200 feet high at the
				peak, with jagged slopes down to a roughly circular
				base with a radius of 100 feet.
				The mountain rises to its full height almost
				immediately, likely with catastrophic results for any
				structures on or above the ground where the spell
				takes effect. A flying creature where the mountain
				appears must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking
				10d10 bludgeoning damage on a failed save or half as
				much damage on a successful one. A non-flying
				creature within the area takes 5d10 bludgeoning
				damage and is abruptly tossed 50 feet in the air
				above the mountain.
				The entire mountain is made of ice, and is
				therefore subject to melting and other natural forces
				as normal, leaving behind a 1-foot-deep crater if
				entirely removed.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school">conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 Action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">1 Mile</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ice Shield" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ICE_SHIELD">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				You conjure a barrier of ice to block incoming
				attacks. You gain a +5 bonus to AC against the
				triggering attack. If the attack still hits, the ice is
				shattered but absorbs some of the impact, reducing
				the damage you take from the attack by 10.
				If the triggering attack misses, then the ice shield
				fuses to the ground to create a 4 foot by 4 foot
				barrier that's 4 inches thick and can provide cover.
				(If you are flying or otherwise not on a solid surface,
				then the ice simply falls.) This ice wall has AC 10 and
				20 hit points, and is vulnerable to fire damage. The
				ice is nonmagical after being conjured, and will thus
				melt naturally.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b>
				When you cast this spell using a
				spell slot of 3rd level or higher, for each slot level
				above 2nd, the damage it can absorb from the
				triggering attack increases by 5 and the hit points of
				a lingering shield increase by 10.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you are hit by an attack</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ice spike" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ICE_SPIKE">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				You conjure an icy, 5-foot-tall stalagmite which
				erupts from the ground at a point you can see
				within range. This stalagmite is 3 feet wide at the
				base and tapers to a jagged point at the top.
				A creature in the space when the spike appears
				must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed
				save, the creature takes 1d8 piercing damage and 2d6
				cold damage and is knocked prone in the nearest
				unoccupied space of your choice within 5 feet of the
				spike. On a successful save, the creature takes only
				half damage and is not knocked prone, but is still
				pushed out of the spike's space.
				If there is no unoccupied space within 5 feet of the
				spike, the creature has disadvantage on the saving
				throw and the spike shatters and dissolves
				immediately after dealing its damage. Otherwise, the
				spike occupies the space it was conjured in until
				destroyed or melted by normal means.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b>
				When you cast this spell using a
				spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the piercing damage
				increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a shard of glass</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ice Ward" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ICE_WARD">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				Your body is encircled by glowing blue runes,
				granting you a barrier of chill magic. Until the end
				of your next turn, you have resistance to fire and
				cold damage.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ice Warrior" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ICE_WARRIOR">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				You conjure a medium creature made of magical
				ice in the shape of a humanoid warrior. The ice
				warrior appears in an unoccupied space you can see
				within range, and disappears if it is reduced to 0 hit
				points or when the spell ends. It is considered an
				elemental.
				The summoned warrior is friendly to you and your
				companions. The warrior acts immediately after you
				in the initiative order. It obeys any verbal commands
				you issue to it (no action required by you), but its
				abilities are limited (see below). If you don't issue
				any commands to the warrior, it defends itself from
				hostile creatures but otherwise takes no actions.
				The ice warrior cannot take any actions except the
				Attack, Dash, Disengage, or Dodge actions. It has the
				statistics of a veteran (Monster Manual page 350)
				except that it cannot speak, its longsword attack is
				always one-handed, it deals an extra 1d4 cold damage
				on a hit, and it lacks the shortsword and crossbow
				attack options. Additionally, it has vulnerability to
				fire damage and immunity to cold, necrotic, and
				poison damage.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b>
				When you cast this spell using
				certain higher-level spell slots, you can summon
				more warriors: two warriors with a 5th-level slot,
				three warriors with a 7th-level slot, and four
				warriors with a 9th-level slot.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Icicle Blast" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ICICLE_BLAST">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				You unleash a wave of cold that causes jagged ice
				crystals to rapidly form on surfaces in the area. The
				ground, walls, and other solid surfaces within the
				area become layered in ice for the duration.
				Affected areas of the ground are difficult terrain,
				and any creature that falls prone on affected ground
				or is forcefully slammed into an affected surface
				takes 1d8 piercing damage (in addition to the
				damage from the fall or other effect).
				Each creature on the ground in the area when you
				cast the spell must make a Dexterity saving throw.
				On a failed save, a creature takes 2d6 cold damage
				and falls prone (taking the piercing damage
				described above). On a successful save, a creature
				takes half as much cold damage and does not fall
				prone.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b>
				When you cast this spell using a
				spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the cold damage
				increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 2nd.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">self (30-foot cone)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Oppressive Cold" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_OPPRESSIVE_COLD">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				You overwhelm a creature with debilitating cold.
				Choose a creature you can see within range to make
				a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, that
				creature is affected for the duration. A creature with
				resistance to cold damage has advantage on this
				saving throw, and a creature with immunity to cold
				damage is unaffected by the spell.
				An affected creature's speed is halved, it can't take
				reactions, and it has disadvantage on weapon attacks
				and Dexterity saving throws. The creature also gains
				vulnerability to fire damage, but ceases to be
				affected by this spell after taking any fire damage.
				A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end
				of each of its turns. On a success, that creature is no
				longer affected by the spell. On a failure, the
				creature takes 1d6 cold damage.
				</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b>. When you cast this spell using a
				spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one
				additional creature for each slot level above 1st.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Refreshing Chill" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_REFRESHING_CHILL">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>

				This spell is a minor magical trick that
				cryomancers use for practice. You create one of the
				following magical effects within range:
				• You create a small, harmless sensory effect, such
				as a sprinkling of snowflakes or a patch of thin
				frost.
				• You chill up to 1 cubic foot of nonliving material
				for 1 hour.
				• You grant a creature advantage on saving
				throws against hot weather for 1 hour.
				• You instantaneously freeze a volume of water
				no more than 1 foot in any dimension.
				If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have
				up to three of its non-instantaneous effects active at
				a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an
				action.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">10 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Reign of Winter" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_REIGN_OF_WINTER">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>

				You grip the area with an oppressive cold. At the
				time you cast the spell, all fires in the area—both
				magical and nonmagical—are instantly extinguished.
				New fires cannot be started in the area, and fires
				brought into the area are immediately extinguished.
				Fire damage cannot be dealt in the area.
				Bodies of water within the area—including flowing
				water, such as a river or waterfall—are frozen solid.
				If a body of water extends beyond the spell's area,
				the portion of water within the area is frozen.
				Whenever a creature enters the area for the first
				time on a turn or starts its turn there, it must make
				a Constitution saving throw, taking 4d10 cold
				damage on a failed save or half as much damage on
				a successful save. Any creature which does not have
				resistance or immunity to cold damage has their
				speed halved and cannot take reactions as long as
				they are in the area.
				If a creature within the area casts a spell or uses
				an ability that includes fire damage, the entire spell
				or ability fails with no effect, and the creature must
				save against the spell as described above. A creature
				which fails the save in this way is blasted with
				retributive cold and is paralyzed until the end of
				their next turn.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school">transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 Hour</set>
			<set name="range">self (200-foot sphere)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Snowball" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_SNOWBALL">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>

				You conjure a two-inch wide ball of ice and snow
				in your hand, which you can launch at your foes as a
				bonus action. When you do so, choose a point you
				can see within range. The snowball streaks toward
				that point, then detonates in a frigid blast with a
				5-foot radius. Each creature within the blast must
				make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 5d4 cold
				damage on a failed save or half as much damage on
				a successful save.
				If you choose not to launch the snowball
				immediately, you can spend your action on future
				turns to increase the spell's power. For each action
				spent empowering the snowball, the size of the
				damage dice improves by one step. The damage dice
				cannot improve beyond d12s. Similarly, each action
				spent empowering the snowball increases the radius
				of the blast by 5 feet, up to a maximum radius of 25
				feet.
				If the spell ends before you launch the snowball, it
				detonates at its current power level. If the snowball
				cannot reach the target point (for example, if you
				targeted a point on the other side of a pane of glass)
				then it detonates upon striking a barrier.
				At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a
				spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases
				by one die for each slot level above 2nd.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">(a small ball of cotton)</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Snowfield" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_SNOWFEILD">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				You conjure a layer of snow that coats the ground
				in a 20-foot-radius area centered on a point you
				choose within range. The snow is 1 foot deep,
				making the area difficult terrain. A creature that
				ends its turn in the snow takes 1d4 cold damage. The
				snow dissolves when the spell ends.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">90 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">(a piece of cotton)</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ash Cloud" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ASH_CLOUD">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				Ash Cloud
				2nd-level conjuration
				Casting Time: 1 action
				Range: 90 feet
				Components: V, S, M (a pinch of soot)
				Duration: Concentration, up to 1 minute
				You create a 20-foot-radius sphere of swirling
				smoke, soot, ash, and embers. The cloud spreads
				around corners, and its area is lightly obscured. The
				cloud lingers in the area for the duration.
				A creature which enters the cloud for the first
				time on a turn or starts its turn there must make a
				Constitution saving throw or be affected by the
				spell. An affected creature's eyes water and sting
				from the hot embers, giving it disadvantage on
				attack rolls and Wisdom (Perception) checks that
				rely on sight. Whenever an affected creature ends its
				turn outside the cloud, that creature can repeat the
				saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a
				success.
				A moderate wind (at least 10 miles per hour)
				disperses the cloud after 4 rounds. A strong wind (at
				least 20 miles per hour) disperses it after 1 round.
				</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
				spell slot of 5th level or higher, an affected creature
				is also blinded.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">90 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">(a pinch of soot)</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Cinder Flare" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_CINDER_FLARE">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				
				You cause an eruption of bright embers to burst
				near the eyes of one creature you can see within
				range. The creature must succeed on a Dexterity
				saving throw or be blinded until the start of its next
				turn.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Consume Flame" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_CONSUME_FLAME">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				
				You touch an open flame and extinguish it,
				absorbing its power. You gain temporary hit points
				based on the size and power of the fire. Touching a
				source of fire as part of this spell does not harm you.
				If the consumed fire is a nonmagical flame the size
				of a Medium creature or smaller, you gain 5
				temporary hit points. The number of temporary hit
				points gained increases by 5 for each size category
				above Medium.
				If the consumed fire is an ongoing spell effect,
				then the spell ends and you gain a number of
				temporary hit points equal to 10 plus 5 per spell level
				of the spell consumed.
				You can also consume the heat from lava, cooling
				and hardening it in the process. You gain temporary
				hit points equal to the radius (in feet) of the area of
				lava cooled, up to a maximum radius of 30 feet.

			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Corona" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_CORONA">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				An aura of dry heat and a faint orange light
				radiates out from you to a distance of 30 feet. This
				area moves with you and stays centered on you.
				Whenever a creature within this spell's area takes
				fire damage from a spell you cast, increase that
				damage by 2d6.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Detonate" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_DETONATE">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				You set off a fiery explosion centered on yourself.
				Each creature in the area other than yourself must
				make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, a
				creature takes 5d8 fire damage, is pushed 10 feet
				away from you, and is knocked prone. On a
				successful save, a creature takes half as much
				damage and isn't pushed or knocked prone.
				The fire ignites flammable objects in the area that
				aren't being worn or carried. In addition, unsecured
				objects that are completely within the area of effect
				are automatically pushed 10 feet away from you by
				the spell's effect, and the spell emits a thunderous
				boom audible out to 300 feet.
				</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
				spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases
				by 1d8 for each slot level above 3rd.

			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">self (15-foot sphere)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Eruption" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ERUPTION">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				
				You cause a volcanic eruption. Choose a point you
				can see on the ground within range. The ground
				within 5 feet of the chosen point becomes difficult
				terrain. A creature standing on the affected area
				when you cast this spell must make a Dexterity
				saving throw, taking 4d6 fire damage on a failed save
				or half as much damage on a successful one. A
				creature must also make this saving throw when it
				ends its turn in the affected area.
				Additionally, four fiery globs launch into the air
				from the eruption site, rising to a height of 20 feet
				before crashing down at four separate points you
				can see within 30 feet of the eruption site. A
				creature within 5 feet of an impact must save
				against the spell's damage, as above.
				For the duration, you can use a bonus action on
				each of your turns to cause the volcano to launch
				three more globs of magma.
				When the spell ends, the fire and magma
				disappear, but the difficult terrain of the eruption
				site remains until cleared.
				</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
				spell slot of 6th level or higher, increase the damage
				dealt by each glob of magma by 1d6 for each slot
				level above 5th.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">(a small pebble and a bit of sulphur)</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Flame Body" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_FLAME_BODY">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				
				You transform yourself into a being of pure flame.
				You retain your size category and general shape, as
				well as your existing features and abilities, and for
				the duration you gain the following benefits.
				You glow with an orange light, shedding bright
				light out to a 30-foot radius and dim light for an
				additional 30 feet. You gain a flying speed of 60 feet.
				Whenever a creature moves to within 10 feet of
				you, starts its turn there, or hits you with a melee
				attack, that creature takes 5d10 fire damage. You
				have immunity to bludgeoning, piercing, slashing,
				and fire damage.
				You can cast fireball as a 3rd-level spell without
				expending a spell slot. Whenever you roll fire
				damage for a spell you cast, roll dice that are one
				step larger than normal. For example, a spell that
				normally deals 8d6 fire damage would deal 8d8 fire
				damage instead.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school">transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">4 Hour</set>
			<set name="range">self (200-foot sphere)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Flame Slash" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_FLAME_SLASH">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				
				You swing your arm in a wide arc, and a stream of
				fire follows along at a distance. Choose a point
				within range. Fire fills a line 5 feet wide and 20 feet
				long from that point, but every part of the line is an
				equal distance from you, thus forming an arc.
				Each creature in the area must make a Dexterity
				saving throw. A creature takes 3d6 fire damage on a
				failed save, or half as much damage on a successful
				one.
				The fire ignites flammable objects in the area that
				aren't being worn or carried.
				</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
				spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage
				increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"/>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">15 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"/>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Flame Vortex" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_FLAME_VORTEX">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				
				You cause a mighty tornado of fire to erupt,
				trapping your enemies in a hellish inferno.
				Choose a point you can see on the ground within
				range. The vortex forms with an interior radius
				between 5 and 20 feet (your choice) surrounded by 1-
				foot-thick flames, which are opaque. The vortex
				reaches 60 feet upwards, and the diameter at the
				top is double the diameter of the bottom.
				When the vortex appears, each creature whose
				space is crossed by the flames must make a Dexterity
				saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 6d8
				fire damage and is pulled into an unoccupied space
				inside the vortex (if possible). On a successful save, a
				creature takes half as much damage and is not
				pulled in. A creature who is not pulled in, either due
				to a successful save or a lack of space, is pushed out
				to the nearest unoccupied space within 5 feet of the
				flames (if possible).
				A creature trapped inside the vortex can use its
				action to try and force its way through the flames to
				escape. To do so, it makes a Strength saving throw.
				On a successful save, it pushes through the flames
				and exits the vortex, unless there is not enough
				space for it or it does not have enough movement to
				leave. On a failed save, the creature remains in the
				vortex. In either case, the creature trying to push
				through the flames takes 6d8 fire damage.
				If a trapped creature does not attempt to push
				through the flames and does not otherwise escape
				the vortex on its turn, that creature takes 3d8 fire
				damage at the end of its turn.
				</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
				spell slot of 7th level or higher, the damage increases
				by 1d8 for each spell level above 6th.
			</p>
		</description>
	
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">6</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
				<set name="range">90 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
				<set name="materialComponent">(a tiny brass ring)</set>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Flame Ward" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_FLAME_WARD">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					Your body is encircled by glowing red runes,
					granting you a barrier of warmth. Until the end of
					your next turn, you have resistance to cold and fire
					damage.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">0</set>
				<set name="school">Abjuration</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 round</set>
				<set name="range">self</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Flame Wreath" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_FLAME_WREATH">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You surround yourself in a brief vortex of fire. Each
					creature other than you within range must succeed
					on a Dexterity saving throw or take 1d6 fire damage.
					This spell's damage increases by 1d6 when you
					reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level
					(4d6).
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">0</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
				<set name="range">5 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Ghostflame" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_GHOSTFLAME">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You extend your arms and release a swirling
					torrent of pure, lightless heat, visible only as a
					mirage-like shimmer in the air. Each creature in the
					area must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature
					takes 7d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as
					much damage on a successful one. If a creature has
					resistance to fire damage, that resistance does not
					apply to this spell.
					The heat from this spell ignites any flammable
					objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases
					by 1d6 for each slot level above 4th.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">4</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
				<set name="range">self (30-foot cone)</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Heat Shimmer" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_HEAT_SHIMMER">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You fill the area with a dry heat that causes
					shimmering mirages to interfere with visibility. The
					area remains centered on you and moves with you.
					A creature or object of Medium size or smaller is
					heavily obscured with respect to any observer
					looking through at least 20 feet of the spell's area.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">3</set>
				<set name="school">illusion</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
				<set name="range">self (60-foot sphere)</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
				<set name="materialComponent">(a pinch of sand)</set>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Hypnotic Flame" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_FLAME">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					Choose a flame you can see within range, such as
					a torch or a fireplace. Each creature of your choice
					that can see the flame must make a Wisdom saving
					throw. A creature that is immune to being charmed
					succeeds automatically, and a creature that is
					fighting you or your allies has advantage on the save.
					If the flame poses a clear threat (such as if the
					building you're in is on fire), then all viewers have
					advantage on the save.
					On a failed save, an observer becomes
					incapacitated and has its speed reduced to 0 as it
					stops to watch the flame for the duration. The effect
					ends for a creature if that creature takes any
					damage, is attacked by a creature it can see, or can
					no longer see the flame.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">3</set>
				<set name="school">enchantment</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 Hour</set>
				<set name="range">60 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Ignite Aether" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_IGNITE_AETHER">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					With an arcane gesture, you cause a creature you
					can see within range to burst into flames. The
					creature takes 2d8 fire damage and must make a
					Dexterity saving throw. On a success, the spell ends.
					On a failure, the creature is on fire and takes an
					additional 1d6 fire damage on the start of each of its
					turns. An affected creature can use its action to
					extinguish the flames, ending the spell.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 2nd level or higher, for each slot level
					above 1st, the initial damage increases by 1d8 and the
					ongoing damage increases by 1d6.

				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">1</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
				<set name="range">30 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Inferno Rain" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_INFERNO_RAIN">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You conjure a swirling cloud of fiery wrath
					overhead, which rains down fire selectively on your
					enemies. The cloud is a 5-foot-thick horizontal disk
					with a 100-foot radius centered on a point you can
					see within range at least 20 feet above you. The spell
					fails if there is not enough room to accommodate
					the cloud, although the cloud can spread around
					corners, and weak barriers (such as windows) are
					destroyed and broken through as it appears.
					When the cloud appears and as an action on each
					of your turns until the spell ends, streams of fire rain
					down on a number of points beneath the cloud up
					to your spellcasting ability modifier. A creature
					struck by a stream of fire must make a Dexterity
					saving throw, taking 10d8 fire damage on a failed
					save or half as much damage on a successful one.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">8</set>
				<set name="school">transmutation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
				<set name="range">200 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Meteor Dash" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_METEOR_DASH">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You wreathe yourself in fire and launch yourself
					like a meteor, flying in a direction of your choice.
					If you would strike a creature, that creature can
					make a Dexterity saving throw. On a successful save,
					your trajectory continues past the creature without
					striking them, but they take 2d6 fire damage from
					the near miss. On a failed save, you strike that
					creature.
					You continue flying in a straight line until you
					strike a creature, collide with a solid surface, or fly a
					distance of 120 feet. Minor barriers, such as simple
					wooden doors or common fruit carts, are destroyed
					without interrupting your flight path.
					If you strike a creature or a solid surface, the
					creature or object takes 8d6 fire damage and 4d6
					bludgeoning damage, and the creature is knocked
					prone if it is Large or smaller. Other creatures within
					10 feet of the point of impact (besides yourself) must
					make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 8d6 fire
					damage on a failed save, or half as much fire damage
					on a successful one.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 6th level or higher, the fire damage
					increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 5th.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">5</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
				<set name="range">self</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Peer Through Flames" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_PEER_THROUGH_FLAMES">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You gain the ability to pass your senses into
					distant flames, allowing you to spy or communicate.
					Upon casting this spell, you become aware of the
					location of every nonmagical flame within 100 miles.
					As an action, you can pass your consciousness into
					any one of those flames. When you do so, you can
					see and hear as though you were in the selected
					flame's location, but you are deaf and blind with
					regard to your own senses. You can continue to
					observe through the flame until the spell ends, until
					you switch to a different flame as an action, or until
					you resume your normal senses as an action.
					While you are observing through a flame, you can
					choose to speak through it as well. Doing so causes
					the flame to take on the rough shape of your face,
					and maintains this visage until you are no longer
					present in that flame.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">6</set>
				<set name="school">divination</set>
				<set name="time">1 minute</set>
				<set name="duration">1 Hour</set>
				<set name="range">self (200-foot sphere)</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
				<set name="materialComponent">(incense and charcoal worth at
					least 500 gp, which the spell consumes)</set>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">true</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Purifying Flame" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_PURIFYING_FLAME">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					Purifying Flame
					5th-level evocation
					Casting Time: 1 action
					Range: Self (30-foot cone)
					Components: V, S
					Duration: Instantaneous
					You release a cone of golden flame that burns
					away impurities. Each creature in the area must
					make a Dexterity saving throw. Undead creatures
					have disadvantage on this saving throw. A creature
					takes 8d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as
					much damage on a successful one.
					For each damage die that rolls a 5 or a 6, one
					ongoing spell or magical effect in the area is
					dispelled unless it is of a higher spell level than the
					spell slot used to cast this spell. The lowest-level
					spells in the area are dispelled first.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage increases
					by 1d6 for each slot level above 5th.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">5</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
				<set name="range">self (30-foot cone)</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Servant of Flame" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_SERVANT_OF_FLAME">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					Servant of Flame
					3rd-level conjuration
					Casting Time: 1 action
					Range: 60 feet
					Components: V, S
					Duration: Concentration, up to 10 minutes
					You summon a group of four magma mephits
					(Monster Manual page 216) which appear in
					unoccupied spaces that you can see within range.
					Each mephit that remains when the spell ends
					vanishes without a trace.
					The summoned mephits are friendly to you and
					your companions. Roll initiative for the mephits as a
					group, which has its own turns. They obey any
					verbal commands that you issue to them (no action
					required by you). If you don't issue any commands
					to them, they defend themselves from hostile
					creatures, but otherwise take no actions.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 4th level or higher, you summon 1d4
					additional mephits for each slot level above 3rd.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">3</set>
				<set name="school">conjuration</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
				<set name="range">60 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Spirit Candles" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_Spirit_Candles">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You create up to three ghostly blue flames within
					range, which hover in the air and burn without
					producing heat or using oxygen. Each flame sheds
					bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an
					additional 10 feet.
					As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the
					flames up to 30 feet to a new spot within range. A
					flame winks out if it exceeds the spell's range, or if
					you cast this spell again.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">0</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
				<set name="range">60 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
				<set name="materialComponent">(a bit of wax and string)</set>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Utter Immolation" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_UTTER_IMMOLATION">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					A vertical column of intense flame erupts from the
					ground in a 15-foot-radius, 30-foot-high cylinder
					centered on a point within range. Each creature in
					the area must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking
					6d8 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much
					damage on a successful one. A creature reduced to 0
					hit points by this damage is entirely consumed,
					leaving behind only ash.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases
					by 1d8 for each spell level above 4th.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">4</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
				<set name="range">60 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
				<set name="materialComponent">(a pinch of fine Sand)</set>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Warmth" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_WARMTH">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					This spell is a minor magical trick that
					pyromancers use for practice. You create one of the
					following magical effects within range:
					• You create a tiny flame in your hand for up to 1
					hour, shedding light as a candle and capable of
					lighting a lantern, torch, or other easily
					flammable material.
					• You warm up to 1 cubic foot of nonliving
					material for 1 hour.
					• You grant a creature advantage on saving
					throws against cold weather for 1 hour.
					• You instantaneously snuff out a flame no larger
					than a small campfire.
					If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have
					up to three of its non-instantaneous effects active at
					a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an
					action.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">0</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 Hour</set>
				<set name="range">10 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Ball Lightning" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_BALL_LIGHTNING">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					You summon a 4-foot-diameter ball of crackling
					electrical energy that bounces around the battlefield.
					When you cast the spell, you launch the ball at a
					creature you can see within range. The target must
					make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 4d8 lightning
					damage on a failed save or half as much damage on
					a successful save.
					At the start of the targeted creature's turn, the ball
					changes direction to launch itself at the nearest
					other creature within 30 feet. The new target must
					save against the spell's damage. This process repeats
					for the duration of the spell.
					If two creatures are tied for the nearest, the new
					target is selected randomly from among them. If no
					new target is in range, the ball waits until a creature
					comes within 30 feet and then launches.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases
					by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">4</set>
				<set name="school">conjuration</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 Hour</set>
				<set name="range">120 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
				<set name="materialComponent">a Ball Bearing</set>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Blinding Arc" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_BLINDING_ARC">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					An electrical spark flashes brightly at a point you
					can see within range. Each creature within 15 feet of
					the flash must make a Dexterity saving throw or be
					blinded for the duration. An affected creature can
					make a Constitution saving throw at the end of each
					of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.
					Charge
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">3</set>
				<set name="school">transmutation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
				<set name="range">60 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Charge" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_CHARGE">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You build a charge while running and then release
					it in a devastating electric punch. After casting this
					spell, before the end of your next turn you can spend
					a bonus action to deliver the punch, which ends the
					spell. The target must make a Dexterity saving
					throw, taking 6d6 lightning damage on a failed save
					or half as much damage on a successful save.
					The spell becomes more powerful if you move in a
					straight line toward your target immediately before
					delivering the punch. For every 5 feet moved this
					way, replace one of the damage dice with a d12.
					Make this substitution before rolling. If at least four
					dice are replaced this way, then a target that fails its
					save is also pushed 10 feet away from you and
					knocked prone.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases
					by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">3</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 round</set>
				<set name="range">touch</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Crackling Burst" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_CRACKLING_BURST">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You blast a creature or object with lightning,
					which then arcs to a number of other targets up to
					your spellcasting ability modifier within 30 feet of
					the primary target.
					Each target must make a Dexterity saving throw,
					taking 5d10 lightning damage on a failed save or half
					as much damage on a successful save. If the primary
					target is wearing heavy armor made primarily of
					metal or is a creature made primarily of metal (such
					as an iron golem) then the secondary targets have
					disadvantage on their saving throws.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases
					by 1d10 for each slot level above 4th.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">4</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
				<set name="range">90 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Decimation Bolts" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_DECIMATION_BOLTS">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					Decimation Bolts
					9th-level evocation
					Casting Time: 1 action
					Range: Self (500-foot lines)
					Components: V, S
					Duration: Instantaneous
					You fire ten bolts of destructive elemental power.
					Each bolt fills a line 500 feet long and 5 feet wide.
					Each creature within the area must make a Dexterity
					saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 20d6
					lightning damage and is stunned until the end of
					that creature's next turn. On a successful save, the
					creature takes half as much damage and is not
					stunned.
					Any spells or magical effects within the area of
					one or more bolts are dispelled.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">9</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">instantaneous</set>
				<set name="range">self (500-foot line)</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Electric Armaments" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ELECTRIC_ARMAMENTS">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					You touch a metal weapon, metal shield, or suit of
					metal armor and imbue it with elemental lightning
					for the duration.
					If the imbued object is a weapon, it deals an extra
					1d6 lightning damage on a hit.
					If the imbued object is a shield or a suit of armor,
					whenever the wearer is hit by a melee attack, the
					attacker takes 1d6 lightning damage.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases
					by 1d6 for each slot level above 2nd.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">2</set>
				<set name="school">enchantment</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
				<set name="range">touch</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
				<set name="materialComponent">a piece of wool</set>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Electric Fence" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ELECTRIC_FENCE">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					Electric Fence
					3rd-level abjuration
					Casting Time: 1 action
					Range: 90 feet
					Components: V, S
					Duration: Concentration, up to 1 minute
					You create an invisible, spherical perimeter around
					a point you can see within range. The area has a
					radius of 15 feet. Whenever a creature would enter
					or leave this area without teleporting, the spell
					delivers an electric shock.
					An affected creature must make a Constitution
					saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 3d8
					lightning damage and until the beginning of its next
					turn its speed is reduced to 0 and it can't gain any
					bonuses to its speed. This occurs before the creature
					crosses the threshold. On a successful save, the
					creature takes half as much damage and its
					movement is not impeded.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases
					by 1d8 for each slot level above 3rd.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">3</set>
				<set name="school">abjuration</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
				<set name="range">90 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Electromagnetic Pulse" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ELECTROMAGNETIC_PULSE">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					Electromagnetic Pulse
					4th-level abjuration
					Casting Time: 1 action
					Range: Self (30-foot sphere)
					Components: V, S, M (a tiny glass globe with silver
					filigree worth 250 gp)
					Duration: Instantaneous
					You release a burst of electric energy that fills the
					area, spreading around corners. Each creature
					besides you in the area must make a Constitution
					saving throw, taking 2d12 lightning damage on a
					failed save or half as much damage on a successful
					one.

					Additionally, each active spell or magical effect in
					the area whose spell level is no more than half the
					level of the slot used to cast this spell is
					automatically dispelled. For each other spell or
					magical effect in the area, make an ability check
					using your spellcasting ability. The DC of this check
					equals 10 plus the spell's level. On a success, the spell
					ends.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases
					by 1d12 for each slot level above 4th.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">4</set>
				<set name="school">abjuration</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
				<set name="range">self (30-foot sphere)</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
				<set name="materialComponent">(a tiny glass globe with silver
					filigree worth 250 gp)</set>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Enliven Corpse" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_ENLIVEN_CORPSE">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					Enliven Corpse
					2nd-level necromancy
					Casting Time: 1 action
					Range: 30 feet
					Components: V, S, M (a dead firefly)
					Duration: Concentration, up to 1 minute
					You force an electric charge into a Small or
					Medium corpse, forcing it to move according to your
					will. The corpse is not conscious and does not act on
					its own—it's more like a puppet than an undead
					creature.
					As part of casting this spell, and as an action on
					each of your turns thereafter, you can force the
					subject to move with a speed of 30 feet and make a
					melee attack with one of its limbs. This attack uses
					your spell attack bonus. On a hit, it deals 2d8
					lightning damage.
					The corpse has an AC equal to your spell save DC.
					It has no hit points, but whenever it takes damage
					you must make a Constitution saving throw to
					maintain concentration as though you had taken the
					damage. The corpse automatically fails all saving
					throws and ability checks.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">2</set>
				<set name="school">necromancy</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
				<set name="range">self (200-foot sphere)</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
				<set name="materialComponent">(a dead firefly)</set>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Gather Power" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_GATHER_POWER">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You store up electrical power for a future blast.
					The next time you roll lightning damage for one of
					your spells before the end of your next turn, that
					damage increases by 1d10.
					This spell's damage increases by 1d10 when you
					reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level
					(4d10).
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">0</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 Round</set>
				<set name="range">self (200-foot sphere)</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Jolt" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_JOLT">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You fire a bolt of electricity at a creature or object
					within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the
					target. On a hit, the target takes 1d10 lightning
					damage.
					This spell's damage increases by 1d10 when you
					reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level
					(4d10).
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">0</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">instantaneous</set>
				<set name="range">90 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Lightning Army" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_LIGHTNING_ARMY">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You infuse up to five willing creatures within
					range with lightning to grant them speed and
					power. An affected creature's speed increases by 10
					feet, and it gains a +2 bonus to AC and to Dexterity
					saving throws.
					Whenever an affected creature hits with a weapon
					attack, the attack deals an extra 1d8 lightning
					damage. Whenever an affected creature is hit by a
					melee attack, the attacker takes 1d8 lightning
					damage. Whenever a creature ends its turn in direct
					contact with an affected creature (such as by
					grappling), that creature takes 1d8 lightning damage.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 6th level or higher, you can affect an
					additional five creatures for each slot level above 5th.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">5</set>
				<set name="school">Enchantment</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 Hour</set>
				<set name="range">150 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Lightning Blade" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_LIGHTNING_BLADE">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					As part of the action used to cast this spell, you
					must make a melee weapon attack against one
					creature within range. Otherwise, the spell fails.
					On a hit, the target suffers the normal effects of
					the attack, and one other creature within 10 feet of
					the target takes 1d8 lightning damage.
					When you reach 5th level, one additional
					secondary target takes lightning damage. Three
					secondary targets are affected at 11th level, and four
					at 17th level.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">0</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">instantaneous</set>
				<set name="range">5 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
				<set name="materialComponent">a weapon</set>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Lightning Blast" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_LIGHTNING_BLAST">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You release a blast of elemental lightning. Each
					creature in the area must make a Dexterity saving
					throw, taking 3d8 lightning damage on a failed save
					or half as much damage on a successful one.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases
					by 1d8 for each slot level above 2nd.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">2</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
				<set name="range">self (15-foot cone)</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Lightning Leap" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_LIGHTNING_LEAP">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					Choose a point you can see within range. You
					teleport to the chosen point through a streak of
					lightning. Each creature in a 5-foot-wide line from
					your starting point to your destination must make a
					Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 5d8
					lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much
					damage on a successful one.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases
					by 1d8 for each slot level above 3rd.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">3</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">instantaneous</set>
				<set name="range">60 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Lightning Orb" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_LIGHTNING_ORB">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					Lightning Orb
					1st-level conjuration
					Casting Time: 1 bonus action
					Range: 60 feet
					Components: V, S, M (a small crystal lens)
					Duration: Concentration, up to 1 minute
					You conjure a 6-inch-diameter ball of glowing,
					crackling light that hovers at a point you choose
					within range. The orb sheds bright light in a 10-foot
					radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. As a
					bonus action on each of your turns you can move
					the orb up to 30 feet, though it winks out and the
					spell ends if it moves outside the spell's range.
					For the duration, whenever you cast a spell that
					deals lightning damage, you can choose to use the
					orb as the point of origin for the spell.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">1</set>
				<set name="school">conjuration</set>
				<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
				<set name="range">60 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
				<set name="materialComponent">(a small crystal lens)</set>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Lightning Rod" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_LIGHTNING_ROD">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					Lightning Rod
					5th-level abjuration
					Casting Time: 1 reaction, which you take when you
					would take lightning damage
					Range: Self
					Components: S
					Duration: 1 minute
					You absorb incoming lightning, taking no damage
					and instead gaining temporary hit points equal to
					the prevented damage until the spell ends. Whenever
					you roll lightning damage for a spell you cast, you
					can sacrifice any number of the temporary hit points
					granted by this spell and add the same number to
					the damage roll.
					As long as you still have any of these temporary
					hit points remaining, your speed increases by 10 feet
					and you have advantage on Dexterity saving throws.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">5</set>
				<set name="school">abjuration</set>
				<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you
					would take lightning damage</set>
				<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
				<set name="range">self</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Lightning Speed" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_LIGHTNING_SPEED">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You infuse your legs with electricity, adding speed
					and abruptness to your movements. Until the end of
					your turn, attacks of opportunity against you have
					disadvantage.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">0</set>
				<set name="school">transmutation</set>
				<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 round</set>
				<set name="range">self</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Lightning Tether" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_LIGHTNING_TETHER">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					Lightning Tether
					8th-level evocation
					Casting Time: 1 action
					Range: 150 feet
					Components: V, S, M (strands of glass filigree)
					Duration: Concentration, up to 10 minutes
					You cause tendrils of lightning to spring forth out
					of the ground, walls, ceilings, or other sturdy
					surfaces to grasp and hold your enemies. A number
					of creatures you can see up to twice your
					spellcasting ability modifier must each succeed on a
					Dexterity saving throw or be affected by the spell. A
					creature more than 20 feet from any solid surface is
					unaffected.
					An affected creature is leashed by animated
					lightning and instantly pulled to its anchoring
					surface. The creature's speed becomes zero. At the
					beginning of an affected creature's turn, that
					creature takes 5d12 lightning damage.
					A creature can break free by spending an action
					and succeeding on a Strength check against your
					spell save DC. Regardless of whether the check
					succeeds or fails, the creature takes 5d12 lightning
					damage as it strains against the tether.
					If a tethered creature casts a spell, it must make a
					Constitution saving throw as though concentrating.
					On a failed save, the spell is wasted with no effect.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">8</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
				<set name="range">150 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
				<set name="materialComponent">(strands of glass filigree)</set>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Lingering Shock" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_LINGERING_SHOCK">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					Lingering Shock
					6th-level evocation
					Casting Time: 1 action
					Range: 90 feet
					Components: V, S
					Duration: Concentration, up to 1 minute
					You place an electric charge within a creature you
					can see within range. The target takes 2d8 lightning
					damage and must succeed on a Constitution saving
					throw or be stunned until the beginning of its next
					turn and be affected by the spell for the duration.
					An affected creature repeats this process at the
					start of each of its turns. If the creature accumulates
					three successful saving throws against the spell, the
					creature is no longer affected.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">6</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
				<set name="range">90 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Magnet Pull" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_MAGNET_PULL">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					You create an electrical imbalance to generate a
					magnetic pull. Choose a metal object that weighs no
					more than 20 pounds. If the object is not being worn
					or carried and is not otherwise restrained, it flies
					toward you where you can either catch it or let it
					fall at your feet. If the target is fastened to a solid
					surface or otherwise prevented from moving, it may
					be possible to pull it free with an ability check using
					your spellcasting ability, at the DM's discretion.
					If the targeted object is being carried, the wielder
					must make a Dexterity save or have the object
					pulled from its grasp and fly toward you as
					described above. If the object is being worn (such as
					one of the plates of a suit of armor), the wearer
					must instead make a Strength saving throw or be
					pulled 15 feet toward you.
					Alternatively, you can target a creature that is
					made largely of metal (such as an iron golem). Such
					a creature is affected in the same way as a creature
					wearing a targeted object, as described above.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the weight of the
					object you can target increases by 20 pounds for
					each slot level above 1st.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">1</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">instantaneous</set>
				<set name="range">90 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Pulse Cannon" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_PULSE_CANNON">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You fill the area with overwhelming electrical
					power. Each creature which enters the area for the
					first time on a turn or starts its turn there must
					make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a
					creature takes 7d8 lightning damage and is stunned
					until the start of its next turn. On a successful save,
					a creature takes half as much damage and is not
					stunned.
					As a bonus action on each of your turns, you can
					change the direction of the spell's area.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">7</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
				<set name="range">self (90-foot cone)</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Raiju Ascension" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_RAIJU_ASCENSION">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					Raiju Ascension
					9th-level transmutation
					Casting Time: 1 action
					Range: Self
					Components: V, S
					Duration: 4 hours
					You transform yourself in a being of pure lightning
					with terrible power. You retain your size category
					and general shape, as well as your existing features
					and abilities, and for the duration you gain the
					following benefits.
					You glow with a yellow or blue light (your choice),
					shedding bright light out to a 30-foot radius and dim
					light for an additional 30 feet. You gain a flying
					speed of 60 feet, and can choose to pass through
					solid objects, although you take 2d10 force damage if
					you end your turn inside a solid object.
					You have immunity to bludgeoning, piercing, and
					slashing damage. You are also immune to lightning
					damage, and any effect that would deal lightning
					damage to you instead grants you that many
					temporary hit points. Any creature that hits you
					with a melee attack takes 4d12 lightning damage.
					You can cast lightning bolt as a 3rd-level spell
					without expending a spell slot. All your spells and
					abilities ignore other creatures' resistance to
					lightning damage.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">9</set>
				<set name="school">transmutation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">4 Hour</set>
				<set name="range">self</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Shock" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_SHOCK">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					A bolt of lightning springs from your outstretched
					hand toward a creature or object you can see within
					range. Make a ranged spell attack. On a hit, the
					target takes 3d10 lightning damage.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage
					increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 1st.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">1</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">instantaneous</set>
				<set name="range">90 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Shocking Aura" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_SHOCKING_AURA">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					For the duration, the area is filled with latent
					electrical charges, filling the air with a faint
					humming noise. Whenever a creature enters the area
					for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it
					must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 7d8
					lightning damage on a failed save or half as much
					damage on a successful one. You can choose to
					exempt any number of creatures from this effect.
					If you would be hit by a ranged weapon attack,
					you can use your reaction to strike the projectile
					with lightning. A nonmagical projectile is destroyed,
					while a magical projectile is deflected harmlessly out
					of the air.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">7</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
				<set name="range">self (30-foot sphere)</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Smiting Bolt" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_SMITING_BOLT">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You summon a 5-foot-radius bolt of lightning that
					streaks down from the heavens and strikes the
					ground at a point you choose within range. Each
					creature in the path of the bolt must make a
					Dexterity saving throw, taking 12d12 lightning
					damage on a failed save or half as much damage on
					a successful one.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">8</set>
				<set name="school">transmutation</set>
				<set name="time">instantaneous</set>
				<set name="duration">1 Hour</set>
				<set name="range">150 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Static" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_STATIC">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					Duration: Instantaneous
					With a word of rebuke, you send an electric shock
					back at the creature that hit you. The attacking
					creature must succeed on a Constitution saving
					throw or take 1d4 lightning damage.
					This spell's damage increases by 1d4 when you
					reach 5th level (2d4), 11th level (3d4), and 17th level
					(4d4).
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">0</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when a
					creature within range hits you with a melee attack</set>
				<set name="duration">instantaneous</set>
				<set name="range">5 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
				<set name="materialComponent"/>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Stormcloud" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_STORMCLOUD">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>
					
					You conjure a massive, swirling storm cloud
					overhead. The cloud takes the shape of a horizontal
					circle with a 100-foot radius, centered on a point you
					choose within range. The cloud is 5 feet thick and
					opaque.
					Whenever an airborne creature comes within 50
					feet of any part of the cloud for the first time on a
					turn or starts its turn there, a bolt of lightning
					strikes out from the cloud at the creature. Such a
					creature must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking
					5d10 lightning damage on a failed save or half as
					much damage on a successful one. If a creature
					becomes airborne while within this area, it too must
					save against this spell's damage.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage increases
					by 1d10 for each slot level above 5th.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">5</set>
				<set name="school">evocationn</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
				<set name="range">100 feet</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
				<set name="materialComponent">scrap of wool fabric</set>
				<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
		<element name="Taser" type="Spell" source="The Elemental Spellbook" id="ID_ES_SPELL_TASER">
			<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
			<description>
				<p>

					You send a pulse of electricity through a creature
					you can see within range. The target must make a
					Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the
					creature takes 2d8 lightning damage and is
					incapacitated until the end of its next turn. On a
					successful save, the creature takes half as much
					damage and is not incapacitated.
					</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<b>
					<i>At Higher Levels.</i>
				</b> When you cast this spell using a
					spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage
					increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.
				</p>
			</description>
			<setters>
				<set name="keywords"/>
				<set name="level">1</set>
				<set name="school">evocation</set>
				<set name="time">1 action</set>
				<set name="duration">1 round</set>
				<set name="range">self (200-foot sphere)</set>
				<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
				<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
				<set name="materialComponent">a bee stinger</set>
				<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
				<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			</setters>
		</element>
	
	</elements>
