<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Bohemian</name>
		<description>Bohemian Background</description>
	  <author url="www.studio-agate.com">Studio Agate</author>
        <update version="0.0.5">
           <file name="background-bohemian.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/th3R3df0xx/Dnd/master/Fate-Forge/Backgrounds/background-bohemian.xml" />  </update>
	</info>

	<element name="Bohemian" type="Background" source="Fate Forge" id="ID_BACKGROUND_BOHEMIAN">
		<description>
			<p>Always on the road, from one town to another, from festival to gathering, you have journeyed thousands of
                miles. You are from an itinerant, nomadic community organized around colorful wagons and dazzling shows.
                You grew up in this seemingly frivolous environment, steeped in a disregard for the conventions of civilization
                that others find both fascinating and disturbing. But let them slander and sneer; the caravan proudly travels the
                roads to the sound of music and to the perfume of exoticism… but also sometimes to the smell of scandal.
                You cannot imagine life without art, without distraction, without embellishment. Soothsayers, fire breathers,
                jugglers, storytellers, dancers, and musicians have always been part of your days and nights. And now, they
                captivate their audiences with tales of your deeds.</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Animal Handling, Performance, Sleight of Hand, and Survival</li>
                <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Herbalism kit or alchemist’s supplies</li>
                <li><strong>Language:</strong> One language of your choice</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong>A costume, a set of traveler’s clothes, a safe-conduct to perform before a lord, the tool, instrument, or gaming set you are proficient in, and a belt pouch containing 5 gp</li>
			</ul>
			<div element="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_A_FAMILY_IN_EVERY_TOWN" />
			<h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
			<p>In the best of cases, you only get passing tolerance from society, but you know that your culture is far-reaching,
                not limited to a single region. Whatever the community you are currently in, you can count on the local presence
                of your own, though as a fringe or grudgingly accepted group. You can always find support from these resourceful
                and generous people and rely on them to get you out of a pinch.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">One language of your choice. Choose two from Animal Handling, Performance, Sleight of Hand, and Survival and ether One type of artisan’s tools, musical instrument, or gaming set </set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill (Bohemian)" Number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMAL_HANDLING|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Tools of the Road (Bohemian)" supports="Musical Instrument || Gaming Set || Artisan tools" />
            <select type="Language" name="Language (Bohemian)" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_A_FAMILY_IN_EVERY_TOWN" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
			<select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
			<select name="Personality Trait" type="List">

				<item id="1"> I do my best to make a good impression wherever I go.</item>
				<item id="2"> My days are split between intense periods of activity and relaxation.</item>
				<item id="3">I rarely spend more than a few minutes without singing, telling tales, dancing, or playing.</item>
				<item id="4">I always dedicate some of my time to helping other people—or at least, my companions.</item>
				<item id="5">I easily get along with other people, without necessarily developing attachments.</item>
				<item id="6">Any public space is an opportunity for me to perform and show off my talents.</item>
				<item id="7"> Whatever must be done, I am game, no matter the danger.</item>
				<item id="8">It is not a disservice to truth to embellish and enliven it.</item>
            </select>
            
			<select name="Ideal" type="List">
                <item id="1"> Party. The purpose of life is to enjoy all the pleasures it can offer. (Chaotic)</item>
                <item id="2"> Laxity. Negotiating, avoiding commitments, bending the rules are all fair play. (Chaotic)</item>
                <item id="3"> Curiosity. My wanderlust is fed by a thirst for knowledge. (Any)</item>
                <item id="4"> Benevolence. Life is harsh for everyone and I devote mine to making those of others easier. (Good)</item>
                <item id="5"> Immorality. The masses bend to conventions, leaving sharper minds like mine free to exploit them. The weak have it coming. (Evil)</item>
                <item id="6"> Detachment. I keep walking because I do not want to suffer after getting attached to places, rules, people, or the past. (Neutral)</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Bond" type="List">
                <item id="1"> My people are spread far and wide, but our mutual loyalty is stronger than anything.</item>
                <item id="2"> I am the pride of my clan, who trust me to bring them fame and to get rid of the prejudices they are the victims of.</item>
                <item id="3"> My beloved made me promise something that goes against my convictions.</item>
                <item id="4"> More and more want to catch me. One day, they may well succeed.</item>
                <item id="5"> The reason I am still free is because I do small favors for powerful people.</item>
                <item id="6"> A member of my family betrayed the clan. I have been tasked with finding them and enacting justice.</item>
				</select>
                     
                <select name="Flaw" type="List">
                    <item id="1"> I may not look like it, but I find it difficult to respect the opinions of those who share neither my roots nor my path.</item>
                    <item id="2"> I like to take risks, but more than that, I like to make others take risks.</item>
                    <item id="3"> I keep making commitments when I should know that I never hold to them.</item>
                    <item id="4"> Better anything than to lose face.</item>
                    <item id="5"> I am often told I am thin-skinned and irritable, which infuriates me.</item>
                    <item id="6"> I always have a hard time believing anyone might want to help me without an ulterior motive.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Feature: A Family in Every Town" type="Background Feature" source="Fate Forge" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_A_FAMILY_IN_EVERY_TOWN">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Within any community, you can find people interested in your spiritual experiments, willing to listen to you and
                aid you. Some of them even get teary-eyed when you mention the possibility of speaking with the invisible and
                the heavens. In time, you have learned to recognize these more receptive individuals who will be glad to lend you
                a hand if you are in trouble. You can always rely on being welcomed and supported (possibly in financial ways)
                by a generally small part of the population, provided you bring them what they expect from you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="A Family in Every Town" />
	</element>
</elements>
