<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Animist</name>
		<description>Animist Background</description>
		  <author url="www.studio-agate.com">Studio Agate</author>
        <update version="0.0.5">
         <file name="background-animist.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/th3R3df0xx/Dnd/master/Fate-Forge/Backgrounds/background-animist.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Animist" type="Background" source="Fate Forge" id="ID_BACKGROUND_ANIMIST">
		<description>
			<p>Not everyone may believe you, but for you there is no doubt about it: you are able to communicate with
                spirits. The spirits of animals, the spirit of every object, the spirits of storms and rivers… maybe even the
                spirits of the dead. You may not have complete mastery over your talent, but you feel the auras, hear the voices,
                and receive the visions. Were you born with this gift, or did it strike you at a momentous time?
                If your culture of origin traditionally accepts gifted people such as you, your condition probably did not bring
                you any trouble, but if you were part of a more skeptical or superstitious society, you most likely had to deal
                with bullying, slander, and perhaps even the threat of being burned at the stake. Fortunately, whatever your
                community was like, you received help from people who see in you an intermediary with the afterlife.</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Insight, Perception, Persuasion, and Religion</li>
                <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Herbalism kit or alchemist’s supplies</li>
                <li><strong>Language:</strong> One language of your choice</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A set of traveler’s clothes, various knick-knacks (of an essentially ornamental nature), and a belt pouch containing 15 gp</li>
			</ul>
			<div element="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_ESOTERIC_APPEAL" />
			<h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
			<p>All animists are aware of their uniqueness. Some take advantage of the influence it grants them while others
                genuinely seek to help other people. However, all are aware that their talent is not universally recognized and
                that they are often taken for madmen or charlatans. Among groups of adventurers, it is rare for every party
                member to be amenable to what might pass for hocus-pocus, but as long as the animist does not overstep any
                boundaries, they should, at worst, only suffer bemused smiles from the more incredulous of their companions.
                Communion with souls is not always the main subject of preoccupation for a hero with this background, but it
                is generally a recurring theme.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">One language of your choice. Choose two from Insight, Perception, Persuasion, and Religion and ether proficiency with the Herbalism kit or alchemist’s supplies. </set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill (Animists)" Number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Tool (Animists)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES" />
            <select type="Language" name="Language (Animists)" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_ESOTERIC_APPEAL" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
			<select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
			<select name="Personality Trait" type="List">
				<item id="1">I often open my eyes wide, the better to see the spirits that wander about.</item>
				<item id="2">My resounding peals of laughter sometimes startle people, even those who are familiar with me.</item>
				<item id="3">Sometimes, I get carried away and go into speeches about entities or concepts, then remember that I am the only one able to wholly understand these truths.</item>
				<item id="4">A metaphor is better than a long speech, and not all sentences deserve to be finished.</item>
				<item id="5">People think I am full of quirks and odd habits, when I am actually communicating with the afterlife and exorcising demons.</item>
				<item id="6">When others give in to panic and adversity is overwhelming, I feel great serenity.</item>
				<item id="7">Most people are surprised, or even repulsed by my dietary or hygienic habits.</item>
				<item id="8">This being refers to himself in the third person, just like he does with other people.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Ideal" type="List">
				<item id="1">Sway. The spirits allow me to influence other people and dominate the weak. (Evil)</item>
				<item id="2">Protection. Every thing has a spirit, but some of them are ill-intentioned, and I must protect the innocent against them. (Good)</item>
				<item id="3">Harmony. The balance and hierarchy of souls and spirits must be reestablished for the universe to thrive. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="4">Flame. Certain entities seek to silence the more creative souls, which must be freed at any cost. (Chaotic)</item>
				<item id="5">Compromise. I must take care that no form of conscience becomes ascendant to the detriment of others. The future of the world depends on it. (Neutral)</item>
				<item id="6">Enlightenment. The gift of communing with spirits is sometimes a burden, but one I bear in the pursuit of revelation. (Any)</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Bond" type="List">
				<item id="1">An entity regularly comes to haunt me. As long as it is more powerful than me, I cannot defy it.</item>
				<item id="2">I must restore the honor of my ancestors through an exemplary existence.</item>
				<item id="3">The spirit of my tribe has been unresponsive, and I must understand why.</item>
				<item id="4">When I was younger, I made a secret promise that I know I will regret one day.</item>
				<item id="5">One person at least is convinced that I am the cause of her troubles and intends to make me pay.</item>
				<item id="6">I must find a relic related to a spirit, for I am certain that the future of the world depends on it.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Flaw" type="List">
				<item id="1">I have become addicted to a substance supposed to facilitate my communion with souls.</item>
				<item id="2">Sometimes, I feel tempted to destroy the bodies of those who doubt the existence of spiritual energy, if only to prove to them that the soul is immortal.</item>
				<item id="3">The spirits appear more real to me than the “living,” with whom I grow increasingly disinterested.</item>
				<item id="4">I frequently overplay my bond with the spiritual to impress other people and am starting to doubt my own talent: am I just a fraud?</item>
				<item id="5">It is said that a dark fate awaits those with my gift. Indeed, I have seen some get lost on this winding path, and I sometimes feel I am not myself any longer. The worst thing is, it does not even frighten me.</item>
				<item id="6">I have performed unspeakable acts in the service of things no one can understand, and I am willing to do more.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Feature: Esoteric Appeal" type="Background Feature" source="Fate Forge" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_ESOTERIC_APPEAL">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Within any community, you can find people interested in your spiritual experiments, willing to listen to you and
                aid you. Some of them even get teary-eyed when you mention the possibility of speaking with the invisible and
                the heavens. In time, you have learned to recognize these more receptive individuals who will be glad to lend you
                a hand if you are in trouble. You can always rely on being welcomed and supported (possibly in financial ways)
                by a generally small part of the population, provided you bring them what they expect from you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Esoteric Appeal" />
	</element>
</elements>
