<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Feats</name>
        <description>The Feats from Fate forge Campaign Setting.</description>
        <author url="www.studio-agate.com">Studio Agate</author>
        <update version="0.0.5">
           <file name="Feats.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/th3R3df0xx/Dnd/master/Fate-Forge/Feats.xml" />  </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Ambidextrous" type="Feat" source="Fateforge" id="ID_AGS_FATE_FEAT_AMBIDEXTROUS">
        <prerequisite>Extra Attack class feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_EXTRAATTACK||ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_EXTRA_ATTACK||ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_EXTRA_ATTACK_MONK||ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_EXTRA_ATTACK||ID_WOTC_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_EXTRA_ATTACK||ID_WOTC_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_VALOR_EXTRA_ATTACK</requirements>
        <description>
            <p><i>Prerequisite:Extra Attack class feature</i></p>
            <p>When you fight with two weapons, your martial skill enables you to perform deadly maneuvers, relentlessly assaulting your opponents. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
            <li>Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
            <li>Extra Strike. When you are wielding a light melee weapon in each hand and take the Attack action, you can use a bonus action to attack twice with your second weapon instead of once</li>
                <li>Double Strike. When you are wielding a light melee weapon in each hand and have advantage on your attack rolls against a creature, if you make a successful weapon attack against this creature and the lower of the two dice would have been sufficient to hit, you can immediately use your reaction to add the damage of your second weapon to your attack. Your ability modifier does not apply to this additional damage unless you have the Two-Weapon Fighting class feature.</li>
                 </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description> 
                <p>When you fight with two weapons, your martial skill enables you to perform deadly maneuvers, relentlessly assaulting your opponents. You gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                <li>Extra Strike. When you are wielding a light melee weapon in each hand and take the Attack action, you can use a bonus action to attack twice with your second weapon instead of once</li>
                <li>Double Strike. When you are wielding a light melee weapon in each hand and have advantage on your attack rolls against a creature, if you make a successful weapon attack against this creature and the lower of the two dice would have been sufficient to hit, you can immediately use your reaction to add the damage of your second weapon to your attack. Your ability modifier does not apply to this additional damage unless you have the Two-Weapon Fighting class feature.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="dexerity" value="1" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Animal Companion" type="Feat" source="Fateforge" id="ID_AGS_FATE_FEAT_ANIMAL_COMPANION">
        <prerequisite>proficiency in the Animal Handling skill</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING</requirements>
            <description>
            <p><i>Prerequisite: proficiency in the Animal Handling skill</i></p>
            <p>You can forge a deep bond with an animal, to the point that it will be ready to die for you. You can lure an animal from the following list: ape, black bear, boar, panther, or wolf. Your leader can authorize other creatures, but they must be small or medium beasts with a challenge rating of 1/2 or lower. You must be in an environment suitable to the chosen animal. Unless circumstances do not permit it, the animal behaves toward you in a friendly manner and follows you curiously. If you treat it well for one week, it draws closer to you, faithfully accompanying you and obeying your instructions like a very well trained dog.Your contact with your animal companion makes it better, increasing its Intelligence to 4 if it was initially lower. Its maximum hit points become equal to half of yours, unless they are higher. Any change to your maximum hit points is reflected on your animal companion, in accordance with the same formula.</p>
                <p> In combat, the animal follows your instructions (provided they remain simple and understandable for a highly intelligent animal) and has its own initiative. As long as you are conscious, you can see it, and it can see you, you decide how your animal companion uses its movement, action, and reaction. Otherwise, it acts in the manner most appropriate to its nature and to the circumstances. Since it must dedicate part of its attention to your commands, it cannot make more than one attack on its game turn.</p>
                <p> You cannot have more than one animal companion at the same time. If your animal companion dies or runs away because you treat it poorly or stop paying attention to it, you can start the bonding process again with another suitable animal.</p>
           
            </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can forge a deep bond with an animal, to the point that it will be ready to die for you. You can lure an animal from the following list: ape, black bear, boar, panther, or wolf. Your leader can authorize other creatures, but they must be small or medium beasts with a challenge rating of 1/2 or lower. You must be in an environment suitable to the chosen animal. Unless circumstances do not permit it, the animal behaves toward you in a friendly manner and follows you curiously. If you treat it well for one week, it draws closer to you, faithfully accompanying you and obeying your instructions like a very well trained dog.Your contact with your animal companion makes it better, increasing its Intelligence to 4 if it was initially lower. Its maximum hit points become equal to half of yours, unless they are higher. Any change to your maximum hit points is reflected on your animal companion, in accordance with the same formula.</li> 
                        <li> You cannot have more than one animal companion at the same time. If your animal companion dies or runs away because you treat it poorly or stop paying attention to it, you can start the bonding process again with another suitable animal.</li> 
                    </ul>
                    </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Archivist" type="Feat" source="Fateforge" id="ID_AGS_FATE_FEAT_ARCHIVIST">
                 <description>
                    <p>You have learned to organize your notes and data in very ingenious ways, granting you the following benefits:</p>
                    <ul>
                    <li>Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li> 
                    <li>Whenever you make an Intelligence (Arcana, History, Nature, or Religion) check, you have advantage on this check if you spend at least 1 minute reading your notes and gathering your memories. You can use this benefit only once on the same subject, and only if you haven’tbalready used the benefit below on this subject.</li>
                    <li>Whenever you make an Intelligence (Arcana, History, Nature, or Religion) check during a short rest, you can forsake your roll to instead resolve your check as if you had rolled a 15. You can use this benefit only once on the same subject</li>
                     </ul> </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>  <ul>
                
                <li>Whenever you make an Intelligence (Arcana, History, Nature, or Religion) check, you have advantage on this check if you spend at least 1 minute reading your notes and gathering your memories. You can use this benefit only once on the same subject, and only if you haven’tbalready used the benefit below on this subject.</li>
                <li>Whenever you make an Intelligence (Arcana, History, Nature, or Religion) check during a short rest, you can forsake your roll to instead resolve your check as if you had rolled a 15. You can use this benefit only once on the same subject</li>
                 
                 </ul> </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
           
            <stat name="intelligence" value="1" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Barfly" type="Feat" source="Fateforge" id="ID_AGS_FATE_FEAT_BARFLY">
        <description>
            <p>As someone used to the rowdiness of nocturnal life and drinking establishments, you have developed the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
            <li>When you are poisoned, you do not have disadvantage on attack rolls, and you have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</li> 
            <li>You have advantage on ability checks associated with gambling games.</li>
            <li>Mist and fog, magical or not, hamper your vision less than normal. You suffer no negative effects from a lightly obscured area, and a heavily obscured area only gives you disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</li>
            <li>You are a veritable night owl, with the vision to match. You gain darkvision out to a range of 30 feet. If you already have darkvision, its range increases by 30 feet.</li>
            <li>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks contested by a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) or Dexterity (Stealth) check.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description> <ul>
                <li>When you are poisoned, you do not have disadvantage on attack rolls, and you have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</li> 
                <li>You have advantage on ability checks associated with gambling games.</li>
                <li>Mist and fog, magical or not, hamper your vision less than normal. You suffer no negative effects from a lightly obscured area, and a heavily obscured area only gives you disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</li>
                <li>You are a veritable night owl, with the vision to match. You gain darkvision out to a range of 30 feet. If you already have darkvision, its range increases by 30 feet.</li>
                <li>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks contested by a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) or Dexterity (Stealth) check.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </sheet>
      
    </element>
      
    <element name="Breather" type="Feat" source="Fateforge" id="ID_AGS_FATE_FEAT_BREATHER">
        <description>
            <p>Whether out of a survival instinct, personal pride, or desperate strength, you can find renewed energy when you are on the ropes. Whenever your current hit points are below half your maximum, you gain the following benefits when you take the Dodge action, in addition to the normal effects:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You can immediately spend any number of Hit Dice and regain hit points in accordance with the short rest rules</li>
                <li>You have advantage on all your saving throws (not just Dexterity saving throws) until the start of your next turn.</li>
                <li>You have resistance against all damage until the start of your next turn.</li>
                <li>You can take the Search action at no cost</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description><ul>
                <li>You can immediately spend any number of Hit Dice and regain hit points in accordance with the short rest rules</li>
                <li>You have advantage on all your saving throws (not just Dexterity saving throws) until the start of your next turn.</li>
                <li>You have resistance against all damage until the start of your next turn.</li>
                <li>You can take the Search action at no cost</li>
            </ul></description>
        </sheet>
        
    </element>
    <!--Devastating Criticals feat not included-->
     <!--Elemental Inurement feat not included-->
     <element name="Fast as Lightning" type="Feat" source="Fateforge" id="ID_AGS_FATE_FEAT_FAST_AS_LIGHTNING">
        <description>
            <p>Your reflexes are exceptionally sharp and quick, granting you the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You can use two reactions between the start of your turn and the start of your next turn. However, these two reactions cannot be used to activate the same effect twice. For example, you cannot make two opportunity attacks within the same round, and a rogue with Uncanny Dodge cannot use it more than once within the same round.</li>
                <li>Whenever you fail a Dexterity saving throw, you can immediately use a reaction to reroll this saving throw. The result of the second roll replaces the first.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
       
        <sheet>
            <description>   <ul>
                <li>You can use two reactions between the start of your turn and the start of your next turn. However, these two reactions cannot be used to activate the same effect twice. For example, you cannot make two opportunity attacks within the same round, and a rogue with Uncanny Dodge cannot use it more than once within the same round.</li>
                <li>Whenever you fail a Dexterity saving throw, you can immediately use a reaction to reroll this saving throw. The result of the second roll replaces the first.</li>
            </ul></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
     <element name="Fate Nudge" type="Feat" source="Fateforge" id="ID_AGS_FATE_FEAT_FATE_NUDGE">
        <description>
            <p>You have a particular connection with the moon Eternity, allowing you to alter a being’s fate to a limited extent:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li>Prognostication. At the start of your turn, you can roll a d20 and designate a creature. Until the start of your next turn, the next time the targeted creature rolls a d20, no die is rolled, and the result of your initial roll is used  instead. If no roll has been made when the start of your next turn comes, this benefit has no effect. Once you have used this benefit, you cannot use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</li>
                </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Prognostication. At the start of your turn, you can roll a d20 and designate a creature. Until the start of your next turn, the next time the targeted creature rolls a d20, no die is rolled, and the result of your initial roll is used  instead. If no roll has been made when the start of your next turn comes, this benefit has no effect. Once you have used this benefit, you cannot use it again until you finish a short or long rest.
            </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
   
    <element name="Ghastly Vigor" type="Feat" source="Fateforge" id="ID_AGS_FATE_FEAT_GHASTLY_VIGOR">
        <prerequisite>The ability to cast at least one spell</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[type:Spell]</requirements>
            <description>
            <p><i>Prerequisite: The ability to cast at least one spell</i></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase the score of your spellcasting ability by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li>Necromantic Surge. Whenever a creature of at least small size that you can see is reduced to 0 hit points within 30 feet of you, you can immediately use your reaction to either cast a cantrip you know or recover a number of hit points equal to triple your proficiency bonus. This does not apply if the creature reduced to 0 hit points is undead or a construct.</li>
               
            </ul></description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Necromantic Surge. Whenever a creature of at least small size that you can see is reduced to 0 hit points within 30 feet of you, you can immediately use your reaction to either cast a cantrip you know or recover a number of hit points equal to triple your proficiency bonus. This does not apply if the creature reduced to 0 hit points is undead or a construct.

            </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase (Ghastly Vigor)" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA" />
        </rules>
    </element>
     <!--Gladiator feat not included-->
      <!--Hardy feat not included-->
       <!--Harpooner feat not included-->
        <!--Herbalist feat not included-->
         <!--Heroic feat not included-->
           <!--Invigorating Abjuration feat not included-->
             <!--Irrepressible feat not included-->
             <element name="Knife Thrower" type="Feat" source="Fateforge" id="ID_AGS_FATE_FEAT_THROWN_KNIFE_THROWER">
        <description>
            <p>Your ease and accuracy with small projectiles is such that you gain the following benefits when you make a ranged attack using a weapon with the finesse and thrown properties:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>As a bonus action, you can make another ranged attack using a weapon with the finesse and thrown properties.</li>
                <li>Your attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover</li>
                <li>Being within 5 feet of a hostile creature doesn’t impose disadvantage on your ranged attack rolls.</li>
                
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description> <ul>
                <li>As a bonus action, you can make another ranged attack using a weapon with the finesse and thrown properties.</li>
                <li>Your attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover</li>
                <li>Being within 5 feet of a hostile creature doesn’t impose disadvantage on your ranged attack rolls.</li>
                
            </ul></description>
        </sheet>
         <!--Magical Reminiscence feat not included-->
                
    </element>
    <element name="Magic Catalyst" type="Feat" source="Fateforge" id="ID_AGS_FATE_FEAT_MAGIC_CATALYST">
        <prerequisite>The ability to cast at least one spell</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[type:Spell]</requirements>
            <description>
            <p><i>Prerequisite: The ability to cast at least one spell</i></p>
            <p>The presence of death focuses your abilities. You gain the following benefits:</p>
                       </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have learned to harness hostile magical energies to fuel your own spells. Whenever you take damage from a spell, you can recover a spell slot of a level equal to or below one tenth of the effective damage taken (rounded down). If you have no spell slot to recover, you gain no benefit.
                      </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
     <!--Magic Collector feat not included-->
    <element name="Marksman" type="Feat" source="Fateforge" id="ID_AGS_FATE_FEAT_SCORCHING_MARKSMAN">
        <description>
            <p>As a condition for making use of this feat, you must forsake your movement on this turn. Whenever you take the Attack action with a ranged weapon against a target that you can see, you can use a bonus action to gain one of the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                   
                    <li>Focus: You cannot have disadvantage to your attack, unless you have disadvantage from multiple sources at the same time. Additionally, your attack ignores half cover and three-quarters cover</li>
                    <li>Take Aim: If your attack is successful, add a +2 bonus to the damage. In addition, your attack scores a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</li>
                    
                </ul>
         
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>
                <ul>
                   
                   
                    <li>Focus: You cannot have disadvantage to your attack, unless you have disadvantage from multiple sources at the same time. Additionally, your attack ignores half cover and three-quarters cover</li>
                    <li>Take Aim: If your attack is successful, add a +2 bonus to the damage. In addition, your attack scores a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</li>
                    
                </ul>
         </description>
        </sheet>
          </element>
             <!--Master Poisoner feat not included-->
             <!--Mixed Success feat not included-->
             <!--Nimble Fingers feat not included-->
    <element name="Ogre Grip" type="Feat" source="Fateforge" id="ID_AGS_FATE_FEAT_OGRE_GRIP">
        <prerequisite>Strength 15 or higher, medium size or higher</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[str:15]|ID_SIZE_MEDIUM</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>Prerequisites: Strength 15 or higher, medium size or higher</p>
            <p>The tremendous strength of your grip grants you the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You have advantage on Strength checks to grapple or shove a creature.</li>
                <li>Any weapon that does not have the heavy property has the light property when you wield it.</li>
                <li>You can wield a weapon with the two-handed property in one hand, in which case you must apply a -1 penalty to the damage of this weapon.</li>
                <li>Whenever you wield a weapon with the twohanded or versatile property in two hands, you add a bonus equal to half your Strength modifier (rounded down) to the damage of this weapon.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>
                <ul>
                <li>You have advantage on Strength checks to grapple or shove a creature.</li>
                <li>Any weapon that does not have the heavy property has the light property when you wield it.</li>
                <li>You can wield a weapon with the two-handed property in one hand, in which case you must apply a -1 penalty to the damage of this weapon.</li>
                <li>Whenever you wield a weapon with the twohanded or versatile property in two hands, you add a bonus equal to half your Strength modifier (rounded down) to the damage of this weapon.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
     <!--Opportunist feat not included-->
      <!--Paragon feat not included-->
       <!--Pincer Attack feat not included-->
        <!--Protective Transmutation feat not included-->
         <!--Rampage feat not included-->
          <!--Rescuer feat not included-->
    <element name="Scorching Sun Warrior" type="Feat" source="Fateforge" id="ID_AGS_FATE_FEAT_SCORCHING_SUN_WARRIOR">
		<description>
            <p>You have learned to fight in a country where the weather is so hot that wearing armor can be not only unpleasant, but even life-threatening. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <p>Increase your Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20. You gain proficiency with shields.</p>
            <p>You gain the Unarmored Defense feature: while you are not wearing any armor, your Armor Class equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Constitution modifier. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While you aren’t wearing armor, your AC equals {{ac:unarmored defense sunwarrior}}. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <stat name="constitution" value="1" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense sunwarrior:base" value="10" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense sunwarrior:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense sunwarrior:constitution" value="constitution:modifier" />

			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense sunwarrior" value="ac:unarmored defense sunwarrior:base" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense sunwarrior" value="ac:unarmored defense sunwarrior:dexterity" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense sunwarrior" value="ac:unarmored defense sunwarrior:constitution" />

			<stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:unarmored defense sunwarrior" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none]" alt="Unarmored Defense (SunWarrior)" />
		</rules>
    </element>  
     <!--Shield Bearer feat not included-->
      <!--Slippery feat not included-->
       <!--Smooth Grappler feat not included-->
        <!--Staggering Strikes feat not included-->    
    <element name="Steadfast" type="Feat" source="Fateforge" id="ID_AGS_FATE_FEAT_SCORCHING_STEADFAST">
        <description>
            <p>Thanks to your experience, faith, or selfconfidence, you are able to overcome ordeals that would break a weaker mind. You have advantage on saving throws against attempts to charm or frighten you, and against effects that might result in madness or corruption</p>
         
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>
                You have advantage on saving throws against attempts to charm or frighten you, and against effects that might result in madness or corruption</description>
        </sheet>
          </element>
    
           <element name="Thrown Arms Master" type="Feat" source="Fateforge" id="ID_AGS_FATE_FEAT_THROWN_ARMS_MASTER">
        <description>
            <p>Your astounding alacrity and fluid movements grant you the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li> Your speed increases by 10 feet.</li>
                <li> Drinking the contents of a vial costs you no action (this benefit can be used only once per round, and only on your turn).</li>
                <li> You ignore the loading property of weapons. When you are prone, standing up uses only 5 feet of your movement.</li>
                          </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>   <ul>
                
                <li> Drinking the contents of a vial costs you no action (this benefit can be used only once per round, and only on your turn).</li>
                <li> You ignore the loading property of weapons. When you are prone, standing up uses only 5 feet of your movement.</li>
                      </ul></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="innate speed:misc" value="10" />
        </rules>
    </element>
     <!--Talent feat not included-->
      <!--Unrelenting Caster feat not included-->
       <!--Valiant feat not included-->
        <!--Weapon Breaker feat not included-->
</elements>
