<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  	<info>
		<name>Avia-ra</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://store.magehandpress.com/">Mage Hand Press</author>
		<update version="0.0.4">
			<file name="Race-Avia-ra.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/th3R3df0xx/Dnd/master/Darkmatter/Races/Race-Avia-ra.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>



    <element name="Avia-ra" type="Race" source="Darkmatter" id="ID_MHP_DM_SOURCE_DARKMATTER_AVIA_RA">
      
        <description>
	    <img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/th3R3df0xx/Dnd/master/image/avia-ras.jpg" height="367" width="400"/>		
            <p>
            The avia-ra are a sun-worshipping race of wingless birdmen, which appear to primitive cultures to spread their ancient religion
            </p>
            <h4>Ancient God-Kings</h4>
            <p>
                Depictions of the avia-ra can be found in the ruins of ancient cultures throughout the galaxy. Often, but not always, they are portrayed as divinity manifest: god-like travelers from the heavens. They arrive as evangelists to share the philosophy of their solar religion—that the Sun Above is the only true god—and remain long enough to build an enduring civilization on the primitive world. Some races consider the avia-ra an ancient and wise people, dedicated to their religion and its tenets. Others cast them as charlatans and false prophets, who routinely prey upon primitive and defenseless peoples. The truth depends largely on perspective, but the avia-ra view themselves only as a grand tool to carry the momentum of the sun's glory to new peoples.    </p>
        <p class="indent">
            <b>
                <i>Avia-ra Names.</i>
            </b>
            Avia-Ra names come in two-part cartouches, with one or both parts of the name being composed of the names of ancient avia-ra heroes and great ideals.
        </p>
        <p class="indent">
            <b>
                <i>Front Cartouche.</i>
            </b>
             Anubis, Apophis, Cani, Canopis, Helio, Horus, Ira, Isis, Nefer, Oculus, Terra, Verum
        </p>
        <p class="indent">
            <b>
                <i>Rear Cartouche.</i>
            </b>
            Amet, Bast, Haten, Hotep, Intef, Lux, Ma’at, Mose, Omet, Osiris, Ptah, Set, Thoth
        </p>
            <h4>AVIA-RA TRAITS</h4>
            <p>Your avia-ra character has the following traits.</p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Ability Score Increase.</i>
                </b>
                Your Wisdom score increases by 2, and your Dexterity score increases by 1.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Age.</i>
                </b>
                Avia-Ra are long lived, and due to their long lives, they have been revered as gods by more primitive beings. They reach maturity at roughly 30 years of age, and can live as long as 500 years.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Alignment.</i>
                </b>
                The avia-ra draw their morality and philosophy from the sun. Though this solar religion can be severe, fatalistic, and dogmatic, most avia-ra have an inclination towards good—or at least lawful—alignments.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Size.</i>
                </b>
                Avia-Ra stand between 5 and 6 feet in height, and weigh roughly 120 to 170 pounds. Your size is Medium.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Speed.</i>
                </b>
                Your base walking speed is 30 feet.
            </p>

            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Languages.</i>
                </b>
                You can speak, read, and write Common and Avia-ra. Most creatures are only able to approximate speaking Avia-ra, for its burbling words are made using the avia-ra’s fluid body. If you are transformed into a creature that has a language, you can speak and understand that language.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Darkvision.</i>
                </b>
                Thanks to the rituals of your ancestors, the light of the sun dances in your eyes and grants you superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Doctrine.</i>
                </b>
                You have proficiency in the Religion skill.       
              </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Avia-Ra Weapon Training.</i>
                </b>
                You have proficiency with the avia-ra sunstaff, scimitar, shortbow, spear, and whip.       
              </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Blessings of the Sun.</i>
                </b>
                Blessings of the Sun. You can cast the spell bless, targeting only yourself, without using a spell slot. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for this spell. For the spell’s duration, if you roll a 4 on the d4 that you add to an attack roll or saving throw, you gain advantage on that attack roll or saving throw. Once you use this trait, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Sun’s Chosen.</i>
                </b>
                Sun’s Chosen. You know the sacred flame and thaumaturgy cantrips. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.
            </p>


        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="2" />
             <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AVIA_RA_DOCTRINE"/>
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AVIA_RA_BLESSINGS_OF_THE_SUN" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AVIA_RA_SUNCHOSEN" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AVIA_RA_WEAPONTRAINING" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Doctrine." type="Racial Trait" source="Darkmatter" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AVIA_RA_DOCTRINE">
        <description>
            <p>
                You have proficiency in the Religion skill.
              
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
	
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION" />
		</rules>

    </element>
    <element name="Blessings of the Sun." type="Racial Trait" source="Darkmatter" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AVIA_RA_BLESSINGS_OF_THE_SUN">
        <description>
            <p>
                Blessings of the Sun. You can cast the spell bless, targeting only yourself, without using a spell slot. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for this spell. For the spell’s duration, if you roll a 4 on the d4 that you add to an attack roll or saving throw, you gain advantage on that attack roll or saving throw. Once you use this trait, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.
           
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>
                Blessings of the Sun. You can cast the spell bless, targeting only yourself, without using a spell slot. For the spell’s duration, if you roll a 4 on the d4 that you add to an attack roll or saving throw, you gain advantage on that attack roll or saving throw. (Spellcasting: Wisdom)
             
            </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
         <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS" />
          </rules>
           </element>
    <element name="Sun's Chosen" type="Racial Trait" source="Darkmatter" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AVIA_RA_SUNCHOSEN">
        <description>
            <p>
                You know the sacred flame and thaumaturgy cantrips. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.    </p>
        </description>
       <sheet>
        <description>
            You know the sacred flame and thaumaturgy cantrips. (Spellcasting: Wisdom)
           </description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SACRED_FLAME" />
        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THAUMATURGY" />
         </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Avia-Ra Weapon Training" type="Racial Trait" source="Darkmatter" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AVIA_RA_WEAPONTRAINING">
        <description>
            <p>
                You have proficiency with the avia-ra sunstaff, scimitar, shortbow, spear, and whip.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false"/>
   
    <rules>
        <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_WHIP" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SPEAR" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTBOW" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SCIMITAR" />
      <!--todo add create weapon sunstaff  <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SUNSTAFF" />-->
    </rules>
    </element>
</elements>
