<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  	<info>
		<name>Amoeboid</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://store.magehandpress.com/">Mage Hand Press</author>
		<update version="0.0.6">
		<file name="Race-Amoeboid.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/th3R3df0xx/Dnd/master/Darkmatter/Races/Race-Amoeboid.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>



    <element name="Amoeboid" type="Race" source="Darkmatter" id="ID_MHP_DM_SOURCE_DARKMATER_AMOEBOID">
      
        <description>

            <img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/th3R3df0xx/Dnd/master/image/amoeboids.jpg" height="367" width="400"/>
            <p>
            Amoeboids are intelligent, vaguely humanoid-shaped, translucent oozes that can mimic the form of any creature they touch. These creatures tend to the maw stations, experimenting into the nature of space and time, parlaying with any creature they meet.
            </p>
            <h4>FLUID ANATOMY</h4>
            <p>
            Amoeboid bodies are almost entirely composed of a translucent jelly-like substance, with a complex network of nerves visible throughout, which emit a dim blue light. Within their heads, a large, brain-like nucleus floats, surrounded by five eyespots spaced radially around it. Their fluid bodies can take the genetic imprint of creatures they touch, molding into an inexact copy, visibly made of the same jelly material. When in this form, however, amoeboids can speak the language of their copy and move in much the same way, allowing them to empathize with virtually any creature. No one is sure exactly how the bizarre anatomy of the amoeboids came to be, for they are among the oldest races in the 'verse and few accounts exist before them. The elves believe that their strange forms were createdon a rogue world, flung into the Black by a catastrophic event, but the avia-ra maintain that their forms are a result of long-term corruption by the Void. There might be some credence to this latter theory, for those that are exposed to the Void's terrible lights and survive undergo the warp and are changed in drastic and horrifying ways, being robbed forever of their previous forms. Perhaps, it is possible that the amoeboids were warped so intensely they were left as mere genetic sludge, lacking any true shape.
        </p>
        <p class="indent">
            <b>
                <i>Amoeboid Names.</i>
            </b>
            Ash (Æ), Chevron (Λ), Digamma (Ͷ), Eth (Ð), Ezh (Ʒ), Gangia (Ϫ), Kai (ϗ), Pilcrow (¶), Psi (Ψ), Shei (Ϣ), Solidus (/), Thorn (Þ), Tilde (~), Yr (Ʀ)
        </p>
            <h4>AMOEBOID TRAITS</h4>
            <p>Your amoeboid character has the following traits.</p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Ability Score Increase.</i>
                </b>
                Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Constitution score increases by 1.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Age.</i>
                </b>
                Amoeboids swiftly reach maturity, growing to full size in a mere 3 years, and have especially long lifespans, living as long as 200 to 300 years.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Alignment.</i>
                </b>
                Natural-born scientists, amoeboids tend to be skeptical and deductive. They lean toward neutral alignments.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Size.</i>
                </b>
                Amoeboids have a roughly similar mass to other humanoid creatures and stand 4 to 5 feet tall. Your size is Medium.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Speed.</i>
                </b>
                Your base walking speed is 30 feet.
            </p>

            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Languages.</i>
                </b>
                You can speak, read, and write Common and Amoeboid. Most creatures are only able to approximate speaking Amoeboid, for its burbling words are made using the amoeboid’s fluid body. If you are transformed into a creature that has a language, you can speak and understand that language.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i>Flexible Form.</i>
                </b>
                You can use your action to stretch, compress, and mold your body into a myriad of shapes. You can transform into any static form that you choose that is no larger than 8 feet in any dimension. When you assume this form, you can replicate something’s basic shape but not its color, texture, moving parts, or fine details. You can’t change your body’s volume, nor can you move, attack, or cast spells while you’re transformed into a static shape. You can also use your action to touch a living creature and assume its general form. Your size and other statistics don’t change. You gain the ability to speak and understand that creature’s language, and if the target has a burrowing, climbing, or swimming speed, you gain those with the same speed, up to a maximum of 40 feet. Your transformation ends after 1 hour, or when you choose to end it on your turn (no action required). If you transform into a form incapable of wearing armor, your armor falls off. You can only take actions while you’re transformed if you are in the form of a creature, and you can only take actions that creature would be able to take.
                       </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i> Amorphous.</i>
                </b>
                You can compress your body enough to squeeze through a 1-inch wide space. You can't expand inside a space that offers any resistance.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>
                    <i> Reform.</i>
                </b>
                Whenever you take bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage from a nonmagical weapon and don't drop to 0 hit points, you can use your reaction to immediately regain 1d4 hit points, up to a maximum of the amount of damage taken.
            </p>


        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="intelligence" value="2" />
             <stat name="Constitution" value="1" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AMOEBOID_FLEXIBLEFORM"/>
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AMOEBOID_AMORPHOUS" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AMOEBOID_REFORM" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Flexible Form." type="Racial Trait" source="Darkmatter" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AMOEBOID_FLEXIBLEFORM">
        <description>
            <p>
                You can use your action to stretch, compress, and mold your body into a myriad of shapes. You can transform into any static form that you choose that is no larger than 8 feet in any dimension. When you assume this form, you can replicate something’s basic shape but not its color, texture, moving parts, or fine details. You can’t change your body’s volume, nor can you move, attack, or cast spells while you’re transformed into a static shape. You can also use your action to touch a living creature and assume its general form. Your size and other statistics don’t change. You gain the ability to speak and understand that creature’s language, and if the target has a burrowing, climbing, or swimming speed, you gain those with the same speed, up to a maximum of 40 feet. Your transformation ends after 1 hour, or when you choose to end it on your turn (no action required). If you transform into a form incapable of wearing armor, your armor falls off. You can only take actions while you’re transformed if you are in the form of a creature, and you can only take actions that creature would be able to take.
              
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>
                You can use your action to stretch, compress, and mold your body into a myriad of shapes. You can transform into any static form that you choose that is no larger than 8 feet in any dimension. When you assume this form, you can replicate something’s basic shape but not its color, texture, moving parts, or fine details. You can’t change your body’s volume, nor can you move, attack, or cast spells while you’re transformed into a static shape. You can also use your action to touch a living creature and assume its general form. Your size and other statistics don’t change. You gain the ability to speak and understand that creature’s language, and if the target has a burrowing, climbing, or swimming speed, you gain those with the same speed, up to a maximum of 40 feet. Your transformation ends after 1 hour, or when you choose to end it on your turn (no action required). If you transform into a form incapable of wearing armor, your armor falls off. You can only take actions while you’re transformed if you are in the form of a creature, and you can only take actions that creature would be able to take.
              
            </description>
        </sheet>

    </element>
    <element name="Amorphous." type="Racial Trait" source="Darkmatter" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AMOEBOID_AMORPHOUS">
        <description>
            <p>
                You can compress your body enough to squeeze through a 1-inch wide space. You can't expand inside a space that offers any resistance.
          
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>
                You can compress your body enough to squeeze through a 1-inch wide space. You can't expand inside a space that offers any resistance.
          
            </description>
        </sheet>
           </element>
    <element name="Reform" type="Racial Trait" source="Darkmatter" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AMOEBOID_REFORM">
        <description>
            <p>
                Whenever you take bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage from a nonmagical weapon and don't drop to 0 hit points, you can use your reaction to immediately regain 1d4 hit points, up to a maximum of the amount of damage taken.
         
            </p>
        </description>
       <sheet>
        <description>
        Whenever you take bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage from a nonmagical weapon and don't drop to 0 hit points, you can use your reaction to immediately regain 1d4 hit points, up to a maximum of the amount of damage taken.
    </description>
    </sheet>
   
    </element>
</elements>
